地球 人类生命的发源地
Earth. Birth place of the human race.
人类与我们大致相近
A species much like our own.
既心怀仁慈
Capable of great compassion...
(公元前17000年)
亦残忍暴虐
and great violence.
我们在保护人类时
For in our quest to protect the humans,
揭开了一些尘封的往事
a deeper revelation dawns.
原来我们与人类早已相识
Our worlds have met before.
这儿 这儿
Here, here.
《变形金刚2：卷土重来》
(中国上海 当日22点14分)
BBC新闻快报
Newsflash from the BBC.
发生在上海的爆炸性新闻
Breaking news at Shanghai.
上海市中心今日发生严重的...
There's been a major toxic spill...
有毒物质泄漏事件
on the Shanghai Central District.
- 市民们... - 今天
- Citizens today... - For today,
我们会为大家关注事件的发展
our topic that's a developing story for you,
一旦有新的进展
we will bring you any new information
会立刻告诉大家...
as we get it...
(五角大楼 NEST部队指挥部)
- 情况怎么样? - 海鹰正接近目标
- What's the status? - C-hawks approaching target.
完成疏散还有三分钟 长官
Three minutes until evacuation's complete, sir.
中国领空已实施封锁 方圆一英里
Chinese airspace has been locked and sealed.
现在开始行动
One mile radius.
好的 NEST部队准备好开始行动
Alright, give NEST team the go.
黑鹰 可以着陆
Black Hawks, clear to land.
叮铃铃叮铃铃 出来拿你的冰淇淋
Ding-a-ling, come out and get your ice cream.
霸天虎都给我听好了
Any bad robot out there better...
等着被我打屁股吧
get ready for ass-whooping.
(霸天虎 舔屁股)
过去两年里
For the last two years,
一支新的汽车人先遣队
an advanced team of new Autobots...
来到地球避难 并加入我的麾下
has taken refuge here under my command.
阿尔茜双胞胎 准备出发
Arcees, get ready to launch.
我们锁定目标并着陆了
We're locked and loaded.
我们大家一起与人类结为盟友
Together, we form an alliance with the humans.
他们是一群勇敢的无名英雄
A secret, a brave squad of soldiers.
好的 听好
Alright, that's enough.
媒体报道说是有毒物质泄漏
Time discovered story in this one is toxic spill.
是为了疏散人群进行搜救
They had to evac the area for search and rescue.
八个月内我们已对敌人作战六次
This makes six enemy contacts in eight months.
这次行动决不能...
We gotta make sure this one does not...
让公众知道 所以务必要保密
get out the public axe so keep it tight.
这支秘密部队代号为NEST
A classified strike team called NEST.
作战目标锁定我们汽车人的死敌霸天虎
We hunt for what remains of our Decepticon foes,
突袭霸天虎在全球各地的巢穴
hiding in different countries around the globe.
马上穿越E区前往A区
Rolling Alpha through Echo now.
好了 铁皮
Alright, Ironhide.
我们到达E区 走吧
We got Echo's. Vamos.
防守两点钟方向区域
To the stacks. Two o'clock.
他在这里
He's here.
我闻到了
I smell him.
接近了 快接近了
It's close. It's heading closer.
哦 不
Oh, no.
怎么样?
How are ya?
有放射线存在
It's three ripple.
好的 大家都保持警惕
Alright, everybody, be steady.
它就在前面
We're right on top of it.
注意火力方向
Ease on fire.
黑豹一号 请求立即支援火力!
Hand to one. Requesting fire mission now!
直升机已就位 马上赶到
Gunships on station. Rolling hot.
我们又发现一个霸天虎
We intersected a Decepticon.
阿尔茜 双胞胎 目标朝你们来了
Arcee twins, target coming your way.
小心!
Watch out!
我搞砸了 还好 没大碍
I screwed that up. I'm okay, I'm alright.
这可是战场 你搞什么?
This is kinda bad, man.What's wrong with you?
快让横炮上
Three insides white.
干净 迅速
Clear and fast.
妈的 我真棒
Damn, I'm good.
空中支援
Air support,
现在就让运输机把他空降下来
we need Big Booter delivered and dropped now.
密码 9-A...
Code 9-A...
下降倒数 五 四 三 二 一
Dropping in five, four, three, two, one.
汽车人 让我来对付那家伙
Autobots, I'm in pursuit.
还不快停下
Pull over.
弱不禁风的霸天虎
Punk-ass Decepticon,
有什么遗言吗?
any last words?
这个星球不是你们的地盘
This is not your planet to rule.
堕落金刚会东山再起的
The Fallen shall rise again.
看来会有麻烦
That doesn't sound good.
但今天不会
Not today.
快点 该走了 都出来吧
Come on, let's go. All hands on deck.
弗兰克 魔球 出去
Frankie, Mojo, out.
快点 孩子们
Come on, kiddo,
- 我们赶时间 - 慢点 老爸
- we're on a schedule here. - Slow down, Dad.
老爸 你这么着急赶我走干吗 嗯?
Why are you in such a hurry to get rid of me, huh?
你把房间租出去了?
Did you rent the room out?
没 不过我倒很想把你那房间
No, I got other ideas for your room
改造成家庭影院
and it rhymes with home theater.
看我找到了什么 你小时候的婴儿鞋
Look what I found. It's your little baby booties.
哦 老妈...
Oh, Ma...
我的宝贝儿子 儿子 你不能走
Oh my little baby, booty boy, you can't go.
你看到了吗?
You see this?
这就是你们该有的反应
That's how you're supposed to react
亲儿子就要踏入社会了
when you free your loins does not...
你就没有点同情心吗?
uncool the world to pep for himself, okay?
行 你上大学...我痛不欲生
Yeah, my heart...Please treat it about college,
郁闷!
bummer.
记得常回家看看 任何假期都要回来
You have to come home every holiday,
别只是重大的节日才回来
not just big ones.
过万圣节也回来
You have to come home for Halloween.
万圣节我回不来 妈
I can't come home for Halloween, Mom.
那我们去看你
We'll come to you.
我们哪儿也不去
No, we're not going anywhere.
你化好妆 我们也会化了妆去的
You dress up, we'll be in costumes.
你们... 你们不能那样
You...You can't do that.
你让孩子喘口气行不 别哭了?
Would you let the kid breathe, for crying out loud?
快点 过来 装行李!
Come on, go, pack!
真是不可思议 你装的行李...
There's no way you're packed...
就好像他要出去旅行一个月那么多 快点!
for a month long trip. Come on!
快点 去呀!
Time-chop. Let's go!
跑步前进 美女
March, young lady.
- 哦 哦 老爸! - 你好喜欢你叫我...
- Oh, oh, Dad! - I love you when you call me
美女 亏你想得出来 老不正经
young lady, you dirty, old man.
不 你还什么没看到呢
Nah, you ain't seen nothing yet.
- 老爸 老爸 老爸! - 怎么了?
- Dad, Dad, Dad, whoa! - What?
我还在看着你们呢 老爸
I'm watching what you're doing, Dad.
这不是教育片啊
It's not a rap video.
教育不就是这样的 不是吗
Just like a coach thing, you know.
我刚才都起鸡皮疙瘩了 老爸
That's a really creepy move just now, Dad.
听着 你是个英雄 呃...
Look, you're the hero, uh...
你妈妈和我真的 为你而感到骄傲
Your mother and me are really, really proud of you.
你是维特维奇家族第一个上大学的
You're the first Witwiky ever to go to college.
现在我又想哭了 好痛苦噢!
Now I'm crying again. This sucks!
会没事的 老妈
You're gonna be okay, Ma.
这对她来说有点 呃...
Now this is going to be, uh...
你知道 难以接受...
You know, hard for her to...
自己儿子长大了 你知道
accept that her boy's all grown up, you know.
就要去自己闯世界了
Going out to handle the world on its own.
- 没事吧 老爸? - 没事
- You okay, Pop? - Yeah.
魔球 不许欺负弗兰克!
Mojo, no dominating Frankie!
还不给我滚下来 你个野东西!
Get the hell of the couch, ya filthy beasts!
哇
Wow.
这种景像在大学里随处可见
You see a lot of that in college too.
爸 你说什么呢?
What are you talking about, Dad?
你会碰见很多女孩子的
There's gonna be a lot of women there.
是 但我是个专一的人
Yeah, well, I'm the one-woman kind of guy.
听着 梅卡拉很棒
Look, Mikaela is the greatest,
但你们要给彼此留有足够空间 懂吗?
but you gotta give each other room to grow, okay?
你们和其他小情侣没什么不同
You're no different than any other couple your age.
不过我们一起发现过外星人
Till we discovered an alien race together.
你们还能一起开那车多久?
How long are you gonna be riding that scooter?
爸 听着 别人有可能分手
Dad, listen, I know what the odds are.
但我们是例外 知道吗?
We're the exception, okay?
等我一下...
Wait a second...
哦 你瞧这是谁?
Oh, who could that be?
两周后就是另一个女孩子打给你了
Two weeks, it could be Muffy.
嗨 美眉
Hey, beautiful.
我们分手吧 山姆
I'm breaking up with you, Sam.
真的吗? 你确定吗? 我觉得你没下狠心啊
Really? You sure? I hear a lot of conviction.
我下狠心了 行吧?
Well, I am, okay?
所以这一次...
So there's no reason for me...
我就不用来送你了
to come say goodbye to you.
哇哦 你这回是来真的
Wow, you almost sounded serious that time.
知道吗?
Guess what?
我要送你一套异地恋爱装备
I made you a long-distance relationship kit.
对 有个摄像头 我们随时都可以聊天
Yeah, I got you a webcam so we can chat 24/7.
爱你无处不在
All Witwicky all the time.
还有些上次战斗的纪念品
I got you a couple of souveniers
你说在电话里不能说的
that you bet that cannot be mentioned on cellphone.
还有唱片啊 蜡烛什么的...
Some mixes and candles and stuff...
真可爱 我等不及了
Sounds cute, I can't wait.
哦 嘿!
Oh, hey!
我那次穿过的T恤要吗?
You want the infamous D-Day shirt?
那件破衣服还留着呢?
You kept your nasty, shredded clothes?
是啊 当然得留着 梅卡拉
Yeah, of course I kept it, Mikaela.
这可是我的战袍 浸透着鲜血啊
It's like my Superbowl jersey. I bled in this thing.
哇啊 你口气不小呀 嗯?
Wow, you're pretty confident, huh?
不 不是那样的
No, it's not that.
我向来没什么自信
It's just that my low...
刚才只是一个小高潮罢了
self-esteem's at an all-time high.
你以为那些个小纪念品
Do you think your little box of souveniers
就能留住我的心了
is gonna keep me from leaving you?
你真该和我一起走
You really should come with me,
学校旁边房子很便宜
they got cheap apartments in campus.
呃 这个现在不太可能
Well, that's not gonna happen
除非我那不省心的老爸走上正道
until I get my man child father rushed out of prison
能养活自己了才行
back on his feet.
我可听着呢
I heard that.
离合器盖子在哪儿?
Where did you put the clutch covers?
凸轮轴旁边
Next to the cam shafts.
我就喜欢你说凸轮轴 再说一遍
I love it when you say cam shafts. Whisper it to me.
凸轮轴
Cam shafts.
你好讨厌哦
Why can't I hate you.
这是家传的魅力
It's my Witwicky charm.
喂 别挂 稍等一下
Wait, hold on. Wait, hold on a second.
我觉得我们不会分手
I guess we're not breaking up.
二十分钟后见
I'll be over in 20.
梅卡拉...
Mikaela...
我衬衫里有块能量体的碎片
I think this little bit Cube got stuck on my shirt.
山姆?
Sam?
哦 上帝! 着火了!
Oh God! It's a fire!
老爸 着火了!
Dad, we got a fire!
着火了!
Fire!
荣恩 我怎么知道会有
Ron, did you know it was gonna be
- 这么难受? - 你别闹行吗?
- this hard? - Can you just stop?
- 好 好 我不闹 - 等一下...
- Yeah, okay, I'll stop. - Just wait...
- 你自己搬东西吧 - 我会... 我会...
- You carry this shit. - I'll...I'll...
- 哇哦! - 知道不?
- Wow! - You know what?
我哪儿都不跟你去
I don't wanna go anywhere with you.
我没心情跟你去法国
I don't wanna go to France with you.
我连遛弯都懒得跟你去
I don't wanna go around the corner with you.
- 好 你行 - 老娘回去看家去
- Alright, fine. - I'm just going back inside.
那我自己去
I'll call you from Paris.
怎么动静这么大?
What is all the racket?
- 哇啊 - 山姆?
- Whoa. - Sam?
- 哇 哇 - 老爸...
- Whoa, whoa. - Dad...
- 那是什么玩意? - 厨卫用具!
- What was that? - It's the whole kitchen!
- 救命... - 哦 我的...
- Help me... - Oh my...
大黄蜂!
Bumblebee!
哦 天啊!
Oh, jeez!
快报警
Phone 9-1-1.
大黄蜂! 回车库去
Bumblebee! Get in the garage.
这些都是怎么回事?
What the frick is happening?
到底怎么了 兄弟?
What happened to restraint, man?
赶快进去 动作轻点行吗?
Just go in the garage, quietly please?
我的妈呀!
Holy mother!
哦 我的天呀!
Oh, my God!
回... 回车库去 快!
I...In the garage, now!
没电了! 警察来了!
Power's out! Get the cops out!
快点 你们这些人 还在等什么?
Come on, you guys. What are you waiting for?
我家房子着火了!
My house is on fire!
- 怎么了? - 过来
- What happened? - Come here.
听着 我要你拿着这个方能量体碎片
Listen, I need you to take the Cube sliver.
你拿着放钱包里 快点
Put it in your purse, right now.
- 山姆·维特维奇... - 我在 妈妈
- Sam Witwicky... - Yes, Mom.
- 我有话说 - 好
- A word with you. - Yeah.
- 嗨 梅卡拉 - 嗨
- Hi, Mikaela. - Hi.
- 我这儿秃了 - 哦
- I have a bald spot. - Oh.
- 炉子太旧了 我猜是 - 烤饼干弄的
- An old furnace, I think. - Become a waffle iron.
你走了 它也得走
When you go, he goes.
我不能让个神经病机器人
I cannot live with this...
住在我车库里
psychotic alien in my garage.
朱迪 嘘
Judy, shh.
国家机密
National security.
听着 如果我们不吱声
Look, if we stay quiet,
他们自然会摆平一切
they're gonna take care of everything.
这一回就当是政府赞助
Just consider this the official...
重新装修 好吗?
start of a remodel, okay?
好吧 如果是政府买单 那我要游泳池...
Fine. If the government's paying, I want a pool...
- 还有喷泉浴缸 - 好的 行
- and a hot tub. - Fine. Okay.
我要裸泳
And I'm gonna skinny-dip...
你要有意见就死定了!
and you can't say shit about it!
伙计 你有麻烦了
Yeah, you know you're a tool.
他嗓子有问题
He's having voice problems.
他在装呢
He's playing it up.
大黄蜂 我跟你说说...
Bee, I want to talk to you...
上大学的事儿 好吗?
about the college thing, okay?
我好兴奋啊!
I'm so excited!
嘿
Hey.
我不能带你去
I'm not taking you with me.
我还是去外面吧 好吧?
I wanna wait outside, okay?
我本想早点告诉你
I wanted to tell you about this earlier.
只是... 你知道
It's just that...You know,
是这样
Here's the thing.
新生不允许有车
Freshmen aren't allowed to have cars.
要是我说了算
I know, and if it was up to me,
我肯定带你去 可惜不行 大黄蜂
I'd take you with me, but it's not, Bee.
听着 你是汽车人
Look, you're an Autobot.
你不该住在我爸的车库里
You shouldn't be living in my dad's garage.
我是说 你在这儿会憋坏的
I mean, you're suffocating in here.
你该呆在更好的地方的
You deserve better than this.
我很难受 兄弟
This is hard enough, man,
别让我更难受了
don't make it harder.
你就看着我 好吗?
Can you just look at me, please?
别这样 伙计
Come on, big guy.
听着 你保镖当得很好 对吧?
Look, the guardian thing is done, okay?
你很尽职
You did your job.
看 我现在安全了
Look, I'm safe now.
你应该回去找同伴们
You need to go be with Optimus Prime and the others.
我也想做普通人 大黄蜂
I just want to be normal, Bee.
所以我要上大学
That's why I'm going to college.
因此我不能带你
I can't do that with you.
咱们也不是...
It's not the last time...
再也见不着面 嗯 伙计
I'm gonna see you, you know, Bee.
得了 别这样 伙计 别让我为难 大黄蜂
Come on, don't do that. Bee. You're killing me, Bee.
但你永远是我的第一辆车
But you'll always be my first car.
我爱你 大黄蜂
Love you, Bee.
哇哦!
Wow!
保险公司 纳税人
Between state farm and the taxpayers,
都会给我们补偿的
we're all taken care of.
- 你身上全是土 - 不用 不用
- You got dirt all over you. - Stop, stop.
- 什么呀? - 我...不用擦
- What? - It's...I'm okay.
哦 看
Well, look.
你觉得没我
So you think you can make it
也可以度过大学几年 是吧?
through those East Coast winners without me?
你的地位无人能及
You're like the best thing that ever happened to me.
然后呢?
And?
- 而且我愿意付出一切 - 然后呢?
- And I'll do anything for you. - And?
我想山姆马上就要对她表白了
I think Sam's about to say the L word.
上啊 儿子
Let's go, kiddo.
真会挑时候 老爸
Nice timing, Dad.
我... 喜欢你
I... adore you.
这不是我要听的那个字
That's not the word that I wanna hear really now.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
意思还不都一样
It's the same word as the other word.
当然不一样
It's not the same word.
听着 我现在即便说了
Look, if I said the other word now,
也是你逼我说的
you forced me to say won't mean anything.
你也从没说过那个字
Plus, you haven't said it either.
所以不许冲我发火
So don't get mad at me for not saying it.
对 我是没说
Yeah, but I haven't said it
因为男生只想逃避责任
because guys always run when you say it first.
对 女生也一样啊
Yeah, well, so do girls.
而且你又不怕没人追
Especially, girls like you with options.
你为了不让我离开
So this is all part of your elaborate plan
才故意不表白 是吧?
to keep me interested?
算是吧
Can be.
不是挺有效的吗?
Ain't those working?
吻一下
Have a kiss.
我们可以的 我保证
We'll make it work, I promise.
那女人有能量体碎片
声波已确认 霸天虎 跟着她
Soundwave acknowledges. Pursue her.
夺回碎片
Retrieve it.
(NEST部队 迭戈·加西亚岛军事基地)
汽车人双胞胎到三号机库报到
Autobot twins, report to Hangar Three.
破冰淇淋车过来啦
Ice cream truck come through.
借过 过一下
Excuse me, excuse me.
嗨 这晚上过的 是 宝贝 该升级了
Hello. What a night. Yeah, baby, it's upgrade time.
对 哦 对 看这儿
Yes, oh, yeah. Look here.
快点 就这儿
Come on, let me call right here.
这不是我的老相好嘛
Time to get my sexy on.
绿的 我就知道
Green, I know,
绿的是我的 我要绿的
Green is mine, I call green.
做我的身体吧
Be my body.
- 我要绿色 - 疼死我了
- I got the green. - That hurt, man.
当然疼啦 踹的就是你
It's supposed to hurt.It's an ass kicking.
全体立正
Stand at attention.
盖洛威顾问 幸会
Director Galloway, what an honor.
我本想带你转转
Let me show you around
但你无权进入绝密区
but you gotta be in the classified access list.
现在可以了
I am now.
总统亲自授权的 少校
Presidential order, Major.
我奉命带话给你那些神秘的外星朋友
I got a message for your classified space buddies.
你们在上海的行动搞砸了
You guys made a mess at Shanghai.
对吧 所以上边用来连线...
Alright, so this is where we...
参谋长联席会议
communicate with the JCS.
而这片区域是汽车人的车库
And this area serves as the Autobots' hangar.
与参谋长专线接通 少校
Secured line to JCS is up, Major.
(美军军用卫星)
现在是五角大楼安全专钱
Secured line to the Pentagon now.
看了上海的行动 是艰难的一天啊
Saw the Shanghai op. It was a rough day.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
我们有情报...
We have intel that...
需要直接进行汇报
I believe warns an immediate debrief.
基于您的许可 我不能让你看到他
Now with your permission, I can't let you see him
但我可以向你转播...
but I would like you to hear...
擎天柱的声音
from the leader of the Autobots.
开始吧
Proceed.
你肯定在想
You gotta wonder.
如果说上帝造了人 谁造了它?
God made us in his image. Who made him?
将军 我们的联军今年已打退...
General, our alliance has countermanded...
霸天虎的六次入侵
6 Decepticon incursions this year.
在每个大洲都有交手
Each on a different continent.
他们肯定是在...
They're clearly searching...
找寻什么
around the world for something.
但昨晚我们消灭的霸天虎留了一句狠话
But last night's encounter came with a warning:
“堕落金刚还会东山再起的”
The Fallen shall rise again.
“堕落金刚”什么意思?
"The Fallen." Meaning what?
来源: 不清楚
Origin: Unknown.
所有的历史
They only recorded
我们变形金刚所有的历史
history of our race was...
只记载于火种源之中
contained within the All-Spark,
也随之一同毁灭
lost with its destruction.
我插一句
Excuse me!
既然你所说的那个火种源现在毁灭了
If this so-called "All-Spark", now destroyed,
那敌人为何没按你预想
why hasn't the enemy left the planet
离开地球呢?
like you thought they would?
盖洛威先生 是美国国家安全顾问
Director Galloway, our national security advisor
总统派他负责联络
the President just appointed him liasion.
呃 我怎么没有得到通知
Well, I guess I didn't get that memo.
很抱歉打断你 将军
Forgive the interruption, General.
借过 让一下
Excuse me, coming through.
借过 借过...
Excuse me, excuse me...
上海的那次行动造成很大损失
After all the damage in Shanghai,
总统 呃...
the President is, uh...
勉强宣布行动成功
hard-pressed to say the job's getting done.
如今
Now...
我们有《外星汽车人合作秘密法案》定下合作框架
under the classified Alien Autobot Cooperation Act,
你们虽然同意与我们共享情报
you are agreeing to share your intel with us,
但从不共享先进武器
but not your advancements in weaponry.
我们已目睹你们人类的好战本性
We've witnessed your human capacity for war.
给你们的话 结果必将会弊大于利
It would absolutely bring more harm than good.
什么时候轮到你替我们考虑了?
But who are you to judge what's best for us?
原谅我插一句
With all due respect,
我们和汽车人
we've been fighting side-by-side
并肩作战有两年了
in the field for two years.
我们出生入死
We've shared blood,
一同流血流汗
sweat and precious metal together.
士兵 打你的仗去 少插嘴
Soldier, you're paid to shoot, not talk.
你别惹我
Don't tell me.
而且 呃...
And the, uh...
- 汽车人又来一拨 - 放松点...
- The newest members of your team... - Easy...
我知道你们是向太空中的...
I understand they arrived here...
汽车人发送了讯息
after you sent a message into space.
公开邀请他们来到地球
An open invitation to come to Earth,
但从未让政府审核过
embedded by no one at the White House.
我先打断你一下 盖洛威先生
Let me stop you right there, Mr. Galloway.
审核就在此进行
It was bedded right here.
而据我所知
And in my experience,
伦诺克斯少校和战友们作出的判断
the judgement of both Major Lennox and his team,
总是准确的
has always been above reproach.
好 即便如此 将军
Well be that as it may, General,
总统认为...
it is the position of the President
眼下国家安全形势严峻
that when our national security is at stake,
没有人能保证做到完美
no one is above reproach.
我们不妨先回顾一下?
Now, what do we know so far?
我们知道霸天虎的头领
We know that the enemy leader,
代号NBE-1 又被称作威震天
classified NBE-1, AKA Megatron,
早就锈成了废铁
is resting in peace
埋于罗伦提恩海沟深处
at the bottom of the Laurentian Abyss,
处于声纳监听系统和潜水艇
surrounded by societs detection nets
全天候的重重监控
and a full-time submarine surveillance.
我们还知道
We also know that
火种源的唯一残片
the only remaining piece of your alien All-Spark
正保存在电磁保险库里
is locked in an electromagnetic vault,
而这个保险库在全世界最安全的...
here on one of the most secure...
海军基地里
naval bases in the world.
霸天虎 我们已锁定火种源残片
Decepticons, we have located the shard.
而虽然没人...
And since no one...
能告诉我 敌人现在究竟在找什么
can seem to tell me what the enemy is now after,
但我...至少能猜出大概
well, there...there's only one clear conclusion:
就是你们 汽车人
You. The Autobots.
他们是来追杀你们的
They're here to hunt you.
不然他们来地球还能为了什么?
What's there to hunt for on Earth besides that?
“堕落金刚要东山再起”?
"The Fallen...shall rise again"?
听上去确实要出大事
Sounds to me like something's coming.
那么我想问一下如果我们最终认定
So let me ask if we ultimately conclude
你们只有离开地球避难
that our national security is best served
才能确保地球的安全
by denying you further asylum on our planet,
你们会和平地离开吗?
will you leave peacefully?
你们应享有自由
Freedom is your right.
你们如果那样要求 我们会尊重你们的要求
If you make that request, we will honor it.
不过 在你们总统下决定前
But before your president decides,
请你问问他
please ask him this.
如果我们走了 而你们错了怎么办?
What if we leave and you're wrong?
问得好
That's a good question.
哦 我的天啊
Oh, my God,
你看看这地方!
just look at this place!
感觉自己已经变聪明了
I feel smarter already.
荣恩 你闻到了吗?
Ron, can you smell it?
是啊 每年四万块的学费
Yes, smells like $40, 000 a year.
好吧 小气鬼
Okay, cheapo.
你先去吧 我们 呃... 我们来搬
Go ahead, we'll, uh...We'll get your stuff.
你去看看宿舍就行
Just go ahead and check out your room.
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
你是山姆吧? 我是里奥
You must be Sam, right? I'm Leo.
你好
Hey.
呃 对不起 我先住上了
Uh, sorry, I already set up the crib.
你想睡哪一边?
Do you want this side or that side?
- 那边 - 我已经选那边了
- That side. - I already chose that side.
你什么意思? 这让人很尴尬
You know what this is? This is the awkward moment.
对 你怕我不正常
Yeah, so you're trying to see if I'm a normal guy.
我也怕你不正常 不讲道理
I'm trying to see if you're a normal guy, balanced
一身是病 总是惹到我
and medicated enough for another coral space.
你讲究卫生我就死不了
Good personal hygiene won't stab me in my sleep.
没犯罪记录 从不偷东西
Good criminal record won't steal anything.
- 没抢过女朋友 - 特别是这条
- Including girlfriends. - Especially girlfriends.
- 有女朋友了吗? - 当然
- You got a girlfriend? - I do.
- 你呢? - 不 还没有
- You? - No, not a chance.
- 喜欢电脑吗? - 嗯
- You're a techie? - Hmm.
很好
Sweet.
沙斯基 法斯宾德 怎么样了?
Sharsky, Fassbiner, where we at?
服务器上线了 里奥
Server's almost online, Leo.
网络可以用了
It works up and running.
非常好 我就想听这个
Beautiful, that's what I like to hear.
- 那是沙斯基 这是法斯宾德 - 嘿 兄弟
- That's Sharsky, that's Spastik, - Hey, dude.
我的IT顾问
my I.T. gurus.
欢迎访问我的网站 兄弟 真实的世界.com
Welcome to my empire, bro. TheRealEffinDeal.com.
就是我 你肯定听说过
That's me, I'm sure you've heard of it.
- 不 没听过 - 呃 真差劲!
- No, I haven't. - Well, that sucks.
- 是什么网站? - 听着 看...
- What is all this for? - See, look...
我挺俗的 我想当个年轻的百万富翁
Call me gross, I wanna be a baby billionaire.
小猫咪日历
Kitten calendars.
从这里起步 你看着我
It's where it started.Look at me now.
要有梦想 老兄
Got our dreams, bro.
里奥 上海那边有坏消息
Leo, we got some bad news in Shanghai.
贴网上去 宝贝 快 快! 浇点油 浇点油!
Post it, baby. Go, go, go! FTJ, FTJ!
- 很清楚 - 浇什么油?
- It's clean. - What's FTJ?
- 火上浇油 火上浇油 - 浇点油 浇油
- Fuel the Jet, Fuel the Jet. - FTJ, FTJ.
就是这个 看到了吗?
This is it. Did you see that?
哇 好的 上海得有一半
Wow. Okay, this half of Shanghai
被毁了 中国说是毒气泄漏
gets rigged when China says gas leak.
肯定骗人的 兄弟
Don't believe the hype, bro.
两年前在洛杉矶外星人对战...
Just like the alien robots in LA two years ago
也没报道
that everyone covered up.
对 我亲眼所见 他们大开杀戒
Yeah, I saw these robots and they did this, like,
从天而降
firing thing and they came down
喷火烧活人
and twisted this woman
- 就好像... - 这是假的吧
- and she was like... - Looks fake to me.
伙计 怎么可能 网上的东西绝对真实
Dude, it's not fake. The Internet's pure true.
- 视频不说谎 - 太假了
- Neither does it lie. - It looks fake.
不 兄弟 我看见过他们
No, man, I've seen them.
他们就像这样 呃 机器人...
They are like these, uh, robots...
看看看 是假的
Look, look, look, it's fake.
谁都可以用电脑做 对吧?
Anybody can do on any computer, okay?
我又没 呃... 没在场
And I wasn't, uh... there.
所以我不能评论或猜测
So I can't comment or speculate.
- 哦 不 - “评论或猜测”?
- Oh, no. - "Comment and speculate"?
你还是我室友吗?
We're supposed to go habitate?
不 听着 好吧 别相信那些东西 兄弟
No, listen, okay. Don't be sucking the sack, bro.
- 什么啊? - 胡言乱语啊
- Whose sack? - Look, the ball sack.
伙计 你火星来的啊?
Dude, what kind of tool are you?
主流媒体都是胡说
Mainstream media sack.
它们在撒谎 知道吧
They're lying to us, alright.
- 真的是外星人 - 好吧 好吧
- It's aliens, man. - Okay, okay.
跟我来
Follow me.
哦哦 里奥 坏了 咱们晚了一步
Uh-oh. Uh, Leo. Bad news, we just got scooped.
机器巨人网上早就有了
The video's already up on GeoBoard.
妈的... 不是吧!
Damn...No!
机器战士老跟我们抢...
Robo-Warrior has a main competition,
独家新闻
our conspiracy step.
连我网站的名字他都敢抄
Effing was my effing idea. He stole it.
他链接到我网站
He's been looking to my site...
疯狂抄袭稿件!
and thieving hits for ever!
对了 我看过你档案
By the way, I read your file.
我穷 你也穷...
I'll pour, you'll pour...
一起奋斗吧?
We're gonna fix that, alright?
你被录用了
You work for me, now.
我被你录用?
I work for you now?
开玩笑 我刚上大学
That's incredible. It's first day of college,
就供职于一家破网络公司
I got a career, a dinky internet firm,
老板人倒不坏
with a boss who is made up...
还真把自己当回事了
of just pure champion stuff.
你嘲笑我的心血是吧 山姆 嗯?
You're mocking my life's work, Samuel? Huh?
先警告你这张嘴 兄弟
That's your one warning patrolling, dude.
别逼我 不然我让他盗了你补助帐户
Don't make me that fast....cause I'll do it.
嗨 好吧 听着
Hey alright, listen.
这房间我住不惯
It's getting a little intense in my room.
- 能换吗? - 可怜的孩子 312
- Can I switch now? - Oh, sad face, 3-12.
不退不换
No switching, no treating.
别老皱着眉头 行吗?
Let's turn that upside-down, okay?
- 哦 到了 - 到了 嗨!
- Oh, here we go. - Hey, hi.
就像霍格沃茨魔法学校 嗨!
It's just like Hogwarts. Hi!
男女混住? 这里男女混住?
Is this co-ed? This is a co-ed dorm.
想见见我室友吗?
Do you guys want to meet my roommates?
- 好呀 - 他们很不错
- Yeah. - 'Cause they're real swell guys.
- 这是里奥 - 我们是维特维奇家族
- Here is Leo. - We're the Witwicky.
- 我叫里奥 - 我叫朱迪
- I'm Leo. - I'm Judy.
嘿 你有个好儿子 他非常棒
Hey, you have a great son. You really do.
哦 你不是最乖的吗?
Oh, well aren't you the sweetest thing?
他确实最乖 妈
He's real sweet, Ma.
对了 你手里拿的是什么啊?
What is that in your hand, by the way?
哦 他们卖我的炒货 为环保义卖的
Oh, I got this at the bake sale for the environment
那帮男生做的
that those boys were having.
你知道吧 很少有白人男孩
You know, you don't often see white boys
留长发而且还扎辫子呢
with the dreadlocks.
- 妈 - 对 这是百分之百的夏威夷
- Mom. - Yeah, it's a 100 percent pure Hawaiian
纯天然的环保食品
green for the environment.
朱迪 能扔掉它吗?
Jud...Can you please drop it?
对 因为他们在里头掺入了大麻
Yeah, then they baked it with reefer in it.
- 不 这是我... 嘿! - 快给我
- No, it's canna...Hey! - Please give me.
嘿! 我今天不节食 想吃就吃
Hey! It's my cheap day. I can eat whatever I want.
天哪 我要疯了
Please God, I'm gonna freak out.
快做点什么 老爸
Please do something right now, Dad.
- 拜托做点什么 - 好了 好了
- Please do something right now. - Okay, okay.
走开 你这个长发疯子!
Out of my way, you wild hair!
巧克力饼我想吃多少吃多少!
I can eat all the freaking brownies I want!
抱歉 伙计们
Sorry, fellas.
抱歉 没什么
I'm sorry and you're welcome.
这儿云集全校美女
There's lot of school beautys here.
这是女新生前五十五强
We call it the Hot Freshmen 55.
沙斯基修改了住宿分配系统
Sharsky hacked campus house and stacked the dorm
调来全部美女
with pretty beddies.
哦 天啊 是她
Oh, my God. It's her.
她来了 她看我了 她看我了
She's coming. She sees me, she sees me.
这个姑娘是我的最爱
She's tight for me on one on my to-do list.
你可不许抢 听到了吗?
Do not bird-dog my credit, you hear me?
女生们
Pretty girls.
嘿 你好 我儿子住这个房间
Hey, you. My son lives in this dorm.
你该和他交个朋友
You should go make friends with him,
- 他很古灵精怪 - 真希望她不是我妈
- he's bad. - Bless she ain't my mama.
他最近刚刚告别处男
And he recently had his cherry popped.
他不知道我当时在家
He didn't know I was in the house.
- 我全听到了 - 嘿 嘿 嘿
- I heard it all. - Hey, hey, hey.
就是他!
There he is!
哦 他该到我的衣橱里 打扮成无敌小帅哥
Oh, He would get in my closet and dress up as Boy Spice.
嘿 他有辆车 是个会说话的机器人
Hey, and his car is a talking robot!
不 其实是个... GPS导航仪 导航仪
No, like a... like a GPS, All-Star.
- 好吧 - 导航仪
- Okay. - All-Star.
飞盘 哇!
Frisbee. Whoo!
不 老爸
No, Dad.
老爸 你带她到处转转
Dad, you're just gonna let her run around school.
- 你还好吗? - 哇啊
- Are you alright? - Whoa.
给我
Give me.
你疯了吗?
Are you crazy?
朱迪 朱迪 放... 放下它 放下它
Judy, Judy.Just...Just put it. Just put it.
看好你母亲
You gotta control your mother.
我不认识她
I wasn't doing this.
嘿 教授 只要给我A 让我干嘛都行
Hey, Professor.I'd do anything for an A.
行啊 坏丫头...
Alright, Grace...
车上有吃的 我们走
Looks like we got some snacks in the car. Let's go.
- 哇! - 那双小鞋呢?
- Whoo! - Did you gt the booties?
对 爸 我拿着呢!
Yes, Dad, I got the booties!
- 好吧 好吧 - 哦 我的天 我倒个儿了!
- Alright, alright. - Oh my God, I'm upside-down!
(军事禁区)
黑狮放射线 我是黑狮探戈 区域西部感应到异常活动
Black Light in X-Trait.This is Black Light in Tango.
B14区被侵入
Breach in B-14.
快 快 快 快 快!
Go, go, go, go, go!
残片没了
The Shard is gone.
干掉它!
Take him down!
- 开火 - 趴下!
- Open fire. - Get down!
这可是兄弟会的第一次派对
The first frat party's the game change of boys,
漂亮姑娘成堆
we're hunting in the wild now,
大伙都痛快玩一把
so get your game faces on.
我不能呆太久
I can't stay long,
我待会儿还要和女友视频聊天
I have a webcam date with my girlfriend.
- 太酷了 - 不 这不酷
- That's so cool. - No, it's not.
你就抱着屏幕亲吧
While he's making up with his MacBook,
今晚我可要玩真的了
I'm gonna be dating my spitzy, freaky freak on.
- 我们走 - 她真性感
- Let's roll. - She's hot.
我们 呃... 去泡妞了
We're, uh...We're hunting.
- 我走了 宝贝 - 再见 爸爸
- See you, darling. - Bye, Dad.
好的
Okay.
(正在连接对方)
我们头一回网聊
This is our first live chat date.
以前从没有过
Never done it before.
我有点紧张了
I'm kind of nervous.
- 你没事吧? - 没事 呃...
- Are you okay? - No, uh...
我来拿餐巾纸的
I was getting a napkin for my drink.
谢谢 干杯!
Thanks. Cheers!
- 你叫山姆 对吗? - 对
- You're Sam, right? - Yeah.
跳支舞吧
I wanna dance.
要... 要跳舞?
Like...Like dancing?
像一对? 像双人舞 像情侣那样?
Like a pairing? Like a duo, like a coupling?
我已经有女朋友了...
'Cause I'm in a permanently, semi...
- 反正我有女朋友了 - 哦 别紧张
- I'm in a relationship, kind of. - Oh, relax.
大家高兴一下嘛
I just want to have some fun.
哦 要高兴一下? 哦 那 好吧
Oh, just some fun? Oh yeah, okay.
我们下棋吧
Let's play some checkers.
你坐在那边 然后...
You can sit over there, and, uh...
- 哦 我的天 - 这样吧 今晚
- Oh my God. - So how about tonight,
我假装是你女朋友
you pretend I'm your girlfriend...
你假装是我男朋友
and I pretend that you're my boyfriend.
(对方不在线)
嘿! 外面草坪上那辆跑车是谁的?
Hey! Who broke the frickin' yellow Camaro?
嗯? 车堵住门口了
Huh? There's a car on the run.
你来干吗?
What are you doing?
休斯顿 我们有麻烦了
Houston, we have a problem.
- 怎么了? - 新来的!
- What is it? - Freshman!
- 对 - 那是你的车吗?
- Yeah. - Is that your car on our bushes?
不 这是我朋友的 他刚去...
No, there's a friend of mine who just went to a...
换衣服了
who went to get you a tighter shirt.
换个鬼 我们查过了
There isn't a tighter shirt. We checked.
想让我踢你屁股吗?
Now how about I park my foot in your ass?
你的脚多少码?
What size shoe do you wear?
嗯 哦 我看你真是...
Yeah, oh, you ain't...
慢着 慢着... 哇啊!
Hold on, hold...Whoa!
你... 你是不是想试试?
Are you...are you trying?
我马上就回来
I'm gonna back it up right now.
出来
Get it out of here.
你还有车?
You have a ride?
兄弟 你竟然不告诉我们?
Bro, why you holding onto us?
我才刚认识你17小时
I've only known you 17 hours.
这会改变我们的生活的
This is gonna really change our lives.
你无法想像
You have no idea.
我喜欢这跑车
I love Camaros.
现在不行 好吗?
I can't do this right now, okay?
你怕什么
Don't be a wimp.
哦 天哪
Oh, God.
- 我第一辆车是我老爸的Z28 - 是吗?
- My first car was my Dad's money 2Z-28. - Yeah?
加满油后
Fuel-injected.
引擎的咆哮声让我浑身兴奋
The roar of the engine. It just, tickles me.
我们 呃... 还没... 我是说 发展到...
We shouldn't, uh, stare...I mean, share stories...
那种地步吧
to each other at all.
你怎么了 山姆? 只是带我一程...
What're you becoming, Sam? Just one ride...
停下 停下
Don't. Don't.
收音机坏了吧?
Is your radio broke?
不 我脑子坏了
No, my car's iteration is.
我们没出轨
We're not cheating.
还没呢
Not yet.
这是怎么了?
Something wrong here?
哇! 哦 天哪! 你没事吧?
Ow! Oh, God! You okay?
我真不知道该怎么跟你说
I really don't know what to tell you,
这车... 毛病很多
this car...it just has a lot of problems.
很多...
A lot of prob...
哦 天哪 哦 进嘴里了 哦...
Oh, God. Oh, it's in my mouth. Oh...
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
我有纸巾 纸巾擦擦脸
I got wetnaps. I got wetnaps for your face.
等等
Hold on.
真对不起!
I'm so sorry!
你想怎样?
What are you doing?
一天都不让我安宁 嗯?
You won't give me a day, huh?
这可是我第一天入学
You won't give me one day in college.
非常抱歉 山姆
I'm sorry, Sam.
但火种源最后一块残片...
But the last fragment...
还是被偷了
of the All-Spark was stolen.
什么? 霸天虎干的吗?
Like what? Like Decepticon-stolen?
我们按照要求将残片交给...
We placed it under human protection...
人类政府保管
at your government's request.
但我来这儿是请你帮助的 山姆
But I'm here for your help, Sam.
因为你们的领导者认为...
Because your leaders believed...
我们把仇恨转嫁到了地球上
we brought vengeance upon your planet.
或许 他们是对的
Perhaps, they are right.
但必须要有一个双方...
That is why they must be reminded...
都信任的人来时常提醒他们
by another human of the trust we share.
- 这不是我的战争 - 还不是
- This isn't my war. - Not yet.
恐怕很快就会是了
But I fear it soon will be.
地球一定不能像...
Your world must not share...
塞伯坦星球那样
the same fate as Cybertron.
万物流离失所
Whole generations lost.
我知道 我... 我想帮助你 真的
I know and I...I want to help you. I do.
但我不是你们驻地球的大使
But I'm not some alien ambassador.
你知道 我只是一个普通人
You know, I'm a normal kid with normal problems.
我做我该做的事
I am where I'm supposed to be.
对不起 我...
I'm sorry, I...
真的很抱歉
I really am.
山姆 我们不能指望天意...
Sam, fate rarely calls upon us...
来改变自己的命运
at a moment of our choosing.
你是无敌的擎天柱 你不需要我
You're Optimus Prime. You don't need me.
我们需要你... 只是你不知道而已
We do... more than you know.
(北大西洋 早上7时13分)
(美国船舶 特贝卡 SSN-754)
方向2-1-4 有可疑目标接近
New contact, bearing 214 and possible hostile
威震天在深海所处位置
confirmed for Project Beat Six drop-point.
- 怎么样了? - 有五个目标
- What you got? - Sue, pull five contacts.
已迅速潜至水下五千英尺
5, 000 feet. Diving fast.
我从没见过下潜这么快的
There's something.They dive that deep, that fast.
进入战斗状态
Man battle stations.
传令 进入战斗状态
Sealer One, man battle stations.
快 左满舵 速度三分之二
Hell, not pull the rudder or head two-thirds.
下潜 下潜
Dive, Cookie.
检测到敌方正发出声纳 上官
The NEST protecting NBE-1 are screening, sir.
此处深达九千三百英寻
That is 9, 300 fathoms down.
- 没有深潜器能赶到现场吗? - 没有 长官
- And no confirmed DSRVs on sight? - None, sir.
那么 各位 麻烦大了
Then, people, we've got a problem.
需要零件
Need parts.
拆掉最小的那个
Kill such little one.
有碎片就有能量晶体
Sea shard, make Energon.
声纳探测到六个敌人
Prime sonar now holds six contacts...
正快速靠近
and they're coming up fast.
马上发碰撞警告...
Man collisional arm...
...距离五百英尺
...are 500 feet.
我们离开这里
Let's get out of here.
天使六号
Angel Six,
有六个敌人进犯
we got six hostiles coming down.
准备撞击 侧翼...
Collision imminent. Portside...
距离一百英尺
100 feet.
准备撞击
Brace for impact.
红蜘蛛 我回来了
Starscream, I'm home.
尊敬的威震天 看到您已恢复
Behold, Megatron, I was so relieved
我就放心了
to hear of your...resurrection.
你竟把我扔在垃圾星球上见死不救
You left me to die, you pathetic insect!
我是在扩充新的队伍
Only to help spawn our new army,
堕落金刚也很生气
the Fallen decreased it,
毕竟 您不在
after all, in your absence,
总得有人来统领大局吧
someone had to take command.
你...
You...
- 太让我失望了 - 小心 小心 别碰坏了小金刚
- are so disappointing. - Hatchlings Hatchlings... Careful fragile.
即便我死了 也轮不到别人发号施令
Even in death, there's no command but mine.
我的主人 此行我辜负了你
My master, I failed you on Earth.
火种源被摧毁了
The All-Spark is destroyed,
没有它 我们的种族迟早灭亡
and without it, our race will perish.
你还有很多要学 我的傻徒弟
You have much to learn, my disciple.
能量体只不过是个容器
The Cube is merely a vessel.
它的能量和真谛永不会被摧毁
It's power, it's knowledge can never be destroyed.
只不过变换了形态
It can only transform.
- 这是怎么回事? - 能量体的能量
- How is that possible? - It has been absorbed
已被那男孩吸收
by the human child.
拯救我们的关键
The key to saving our race...
就在他的大脑里
now lies within his mind.
这样的话
Well then,
让我把他的大脑生生给拿出来
let me strip the very flesh from his body.
你会的 我的徒弟 迟早会的
And you will, my apprentice.
千年以来 我一直梦想能回到
In time. For millenia, I have dreamed of my return
那个被毁灭的星球
to that wretched planet,
那时我与汽车人还情同手足
where I too was once betrayed,
可他们竟然背叛了我
by the Primes I call my brothers.
只有超级领袖才能打败我
Only a Prime can defeat me,
但是现在只剩一个超级领袖
and now only one remains.
擎天柱 是他在保护那个男孩
Optimus. He protects the boy.
那么这个男孩就可以带我们找到他
Then the boy will lead us to him
- 这个仇我一定要报 - 是的
- and revenge will be ours. - Yes.
那男孩跑不掉的
The boy will not escape us.
他一直在我们的监视下
We have him in our sights.
但是不补充能量的话 这些新生儿就会死掉
Without more Energon, hatchlings will keep dying.
空间 时间 引力
Space, time, gravity.
- 谢谢 - 帮我吃完吧
- Thank you. - Finish that for me.
今天我和你们将要开始一段旅程
We're going on a journey together, you and I, today.
你们正值青春年少
All you, eager nubile young minds...
难怪精力过剩
on the very cusp of adulthood.
我是你们的伙伴 是向导 是灵魂伴侣
And I shall be your consort, your guide,
我能发掘你们的阴暗面
your chaperone, into the heart of darkness.
欢迎听我的天文课
Welcome to Astronomy 101.
我们对星星的了解有多少?
For what do we know about the stars?
处女座... 处女
Virgo... the virgin.
猎户座 也就是射手座
Orion, the great hunter.
可它们没有闪耀的钻石
These are no mere twinkling diamonds
供纯情少女们日思夜想
for lovely maidens to wish upon.
它们产生的能量规模大的惊人
No, they are diamond, filled with a throbbing,
随时要喷薄爆发出能量
savage and hemped-up energy.
来看看阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦
Behold the work of Albert Einstein,
那位曾和我一样的老教授的理论
a professor once, like moi,
- 能量等于质量乘以... - 你在干什么?
- energy, in its mass temp... - What are you doing?
把手放下 把手放下
Put your hand down, put your hand down.
年轻人 上我的课
Young man, there are no questions...
到课堂高潮之时再提问
until I've reached the climax of my lecture.
我看完了你的书
I've just finished your book.
只有一个问题
There's only one problem.
爱因斯坦错了
Einstein's wrong.
一维空间中能量是等于质量乘以速度的平方
Energy doesn't go mass times velocity light square
那其它十七维空间呢
in this dimension.What about the other 17
没人讨论这些?
while we're impossible to give 17?
举例来说:
A clear example:
如果将能量晶体分解
Break down the elemental components of Energon,
并假定一个常量的衰减速率
assume a constant decay rate and extrapolate for each of the...
通过反射那些超级领袖反射的信号
Fourteen galactic convergences it took the Sentinel Prime expedition to receive an... Echo on its signal,
就能为交互空间能量发生得出一个公式
you wind up with a formula for inter-dimensional energy increase...
质量和光速不可能如此解释
that mass and light alone can't possibly explain.
大家都说说 没有人同意我吗?
Come on, guys, I can't be the only one in class...
小伙子
Young man,
你不能当着系主任的面羞辱我
I will not be punked in front of the dean.
听好 这里我说了算 知道吗?
No, this is my universe here. Do you understand?
我就是一切 我就是神灵
I am the Alpha and the Omega.
- 立刻给我出去 - 是 先生
- Get out of my class. - Yes, sir.
各位 还有谁还打算
Any one else care to...
当堂精神崩溃?
have some sort of mental breakdown?
嗨 大骨头 嗨!
Hi, Bones. Hi!
嗨! 哦 好 真是个乖孩子
Hi! Oh yes, that's a good boy.
哦 你今天真乖 太乖了
Oh, what a good boy, you are.
嘿 大骨头
Hey, Bones.
你饿吗?
You hungry?
快吃吧
Here you go.
- 好 山姆 - 喂? 梅卡拉
- Yes, Samuel. - Hello? Mikaela.
我不相信第一次视频约会
I can't believe you're gonna stand me up
你就失约了
on our first web chat date.
出状况了 知道吗?
Something just happened to me, okay?
怎么 泡到美女啦?
Wait, you finally hit puberty?
不 不 别开玩笑 说真的
No, no, no, Stop laughing. This is serious.
好啦 记得我提到过
Okay, remember I was telling you about
我曾曾曾祖父吗 阿奇巴德·维特维奇?
my great-great-grandfather, Archibald Witwicky?
记得吗?
Do you remember?
看着点!你走哪儿去了!
Watch where you're supposed to go!
好的 我当时不是说吗 好...
Okay, remember I was telling you about, okay...
你不能停下吗... 给我看着点! 别踩着!
Can you stop...Watch the foot! Watch your foot!
梅卡拉 好 曾曾曾祖父
Mikaela, okay, my great-great-grandfather
去了北极 对吧?
went to this Arctic mission, right?
然后他看到了威震天 威震天电了他
And he saw Megatron, Megatron zapped him
然后他就开始看到些疯狂的符号 对吧
and he started seeing these crazy symbols, okay.
呃 现在我也看到了 对不起
Well, now I'm seeing them too. Excuse me.
我看完903页天文学课本
I just wrote a 903-page Astronomy...
只用了32.6秒
book at 32.6 seconds
我在课堂上精神失常得一塌糊涂
and had a meltdown in the middle of my class.
我看到符号了自从我...
I am seeing symbols ever since I...
自从什么?
Since what?
自从接触能量体碎片
Ever since I touched the Cube sliver.
东西还在吧?
Do you have it?
在 我放在店里保险箱里呢 它很安全
Yeah, I have it. It's in the shop safe. It's fine.
梅...梅卡拉 不要碰它 好吗? 别碰它
Mi...Mikaela, do not touch it, okay? Don't touch it.
我不会碰它
I'm not gonna touch it,
山姆 它很好
Sam, it's fine.
锁着呢 没人知道位置
It's locked away, no one knows where it is.
但我知道
But I do.
你很性感 可是很蠢
You're hot, but you're ain't too bright.
开工了
There we go.
哦 真他妈可恶!
Oh, big son of a bitch!
看什么看 呆瓜?
What are you looking at, Slobberpuss?
啊 怎么...
Ah, what the...
我恨这个见鬼的破地方了!
This is a fricking House of Horrors.
等等
Hold on.
向右转到5...
Right to five, then...
你就这么点能耐吗 嗯?
Is that the best you got, huh?
你就这么点能耐吗?
Is that the best you can do?
你想干什么 小畜生?
What are you doing here, you little freak?
哦 那是我的眼睛 疯女人!
Ow, that's my eye, you crazy bitch!
还不快交代?
You gotta talk now?
我...我来找能量体的真谛
I... I seek knowledge of the Cube.
堕落金刚派我来的
The Fallen demands me.
什么真谛?
What knowledge?
你有碎片 我需要它
You got the shot, I need the shot,
把它给我 给我碎片
give me the shot, I need the shot.
把它给我 他们会宰了我的
Give me the shot, they're gonna whack me,
我拿不到碎片他们会杀了我
I'm gonna be dead without that shot.
轻点 美少女战士
Easy, Warrior Goddess,
我只是替人卖命的小角色
I'm just a little salvage scrap drone.
那就做你的噩梦吧
Then I'm your worst nightmare.
嘿 嘿!
Hey, hey!
- 那是什么东西? - 回头再说
- What the hell was that? - I'll tell you later,
电话里不方便 知道吗?
just not on open phone line, okay?
我现在就去机场
I'm gonna get on a plane right now.
今天下午就能到了
I'll be there later this afternoon.
小心点 山姆
Just be careful, Sam.
今天有没有陌生人...
And have any stranger giving you...
让你带可疑物品?
anything suspicious to carry on today?
有! 遥控炸弹!
Yeah, a large box!
- 没有 - 很好
- No. - Good.
少校 汽车人发来求救信号
Major, incoming SOS from Autobots.
多个霸天虎开始行动
Multiple Decepticon contacts in motion.
正在接近美国东部 长官
Vicinity eastern United States, sir.
- 哈斯文 他们有多少? - 还不清楚 长官
- Hansvin, how many? - Unclear, sir.
那 快点弄清楚
Well, get clear.
汽车人出动了
Autobots on the move.
他们分成两个小分队 长官
Splitting them into two teams, sir.
它们不回应呼叫
Unarching their course,
在向纽约和费城开进
somewhere heading to New York and Philadelphia.
好的 全副武装
Full weapons deployment.
二十分钟后起飞!
Wheels up in 20 minutes!
爱丽丝 亲爱的
Alicia, my lover.
来份超大比萨怎么样?
Can I interest you in Mayteam Zookeeper's Special?
超大奶酪
Extra large supertees with...
每种肉都有
very known animal as a topping.
这肉饼直径有18英寸
Basic lengths. Only 18 inches of meat.
哦 你是素食者
Oh, so you're a vegetarian.
好吧 没事 我也是
Alright, it's cool. I am too.
山姆在吗?
Is Sam home?
山姆... 大概死了吧 不清楚
Sam... I think he died but, why don't we check?
- 到了 - 嘿
- Here we are.- Hey.
你有没有过脑子里总是反覆放同一首歌?
Have you had a song stuck in yours?
很难听 但你却忍不住
It's like the worst song ever, but you can't help
一直哼着 就这样 来回放
whistle it or sing it.It's like, repeats itself,
来回放 来回放
repeats itself, repeats itself,
来回放... 猫咪日历 猫咪日历
repeats itself...Kitten calendar, kitten calendar,
- 猫咪日历 猫咪日历 - 兄弟
- kitten calendar, kitten calendar... - Dude,
怎么啦?
What the F?
我知道你要崩溃
I know you're freaking out.
别崩溃 别崩溃
Don't freak out, don't freak out.
可以补救 我脑子里的迷和代码
Easy fix. Puzzle, code, in my head.
都在墙上写着呢
Now it's on the walls.
全部都在 多棒啊
Everything is good.
这部分...
This is the part that...
好的 说到哪儿了?
Okay, what were you saying?
爱丽丝 对不起把你吓着了 我们走
Alice, I'm horrified you had to see this. Let's go.
- 出去 - 什么?
- Get out. - What?
等等 等等 等等 我...我能旁听吗?
Wait, wait, wait. C...Can I just sit and watch?
我...我不说话 我吃比萨
I...I'll eat my pizza quietly.
山姆 我知道你有非同常人之处
Sam, I knew there were something special about you.
是吗?
Really?
你我心里都很清楚
And I know you know what happens
我们同处一室会发生什么...
when two people in the room get together...
无限惊喜... 在床上
they're genuinely amazing...in bed.
- 谢谢你 - 不客气
- Thank you. - No problem.
好吧 等等
Alright, listen, hold on.
注意 别越轨
Boundaries. Flight on the plane.
好吧 我很怕痒
Okay, I'm very ticklish.
我们都有需要 山姆 放松!
You have the need, Sam. Relax!
什么呀?
Why?
哦 天啊!
Oh, jeez!
呃 聊聊金融危机吧? 挺刺激 对吧?
Uh, what about this economy? It's crazy, isn't it?
- 你也太主动了 - 放松就好
- You are very aggressive. - Just relax.
要土耳其面包吗?
You want some jerky meatloaf?
山姆?
Sam?
梅卡拉
Mikaela.
你女朋友?
Is that your girlfriend?
前女友
Ex.
梅卡拉 等等... 你听我解释...
Mikaela, wait...I can explain every...
山姆 你的床友 爱丽丝
Sam, your bed-buddy, Alice.
什么...
What...
- 来了! - 是女外星人
- It's coming! - This is an alien robot.
- 你得走 快跑 - 真的吗?
- You gotta move. Just run. - They're real?
哦 我的天
Oh my God,
难以置信 我梦里还跟她亲热来着
I can't believe I once had sex with her in my dream.
你可真是想念我啊 山姆
I can tell that you really missed me a lot, Sam.
听着 这不是我的错 好吧?
Look, it's not my fault, okay?
听着 听着 我是受害人
Listen, listen. I'm a victim.
哦 你是受害人? 受什么害?
Oh, you were a victim? Of what?
- 受什么害? 一个80磅的女孩... - 受... 受...
- Of what? A little 80-pound girl... - Of...Of...
你的脖子就像被...
It's like getting humped...
一头野母牛骚扰了一样
in the neck by a mountain ox.
你不该把舌头放她嘴里
You didn't have to put your tongue in her mouth.
- 我没有 - 你有
- I didn't. - You did.
听着 是她把五尺长舌头
Look, you ever had your stomach tounged
伸进我胃里了?
by a mountain ox with a 5-foot tong?
我不觉得这好玩 好了 梅卡拉
It's not fun for me, okay, Mikaela.
而且闻起来像...柴油
And it smelled like...like diesel.
柴油味满嘴都是
Like a diesel he dinged to it.
你怎么像个小女生似的
You're such a little girl.
我们俩先沉默十秒钟 现在
You have ten seconds of silence, right now.
十秒内不和你说话
I'm not talking to you for ten seconds.
不 你还敢叫我闭嘴 你知道吗?
No, you can't give me the silence. You know what?
我十秒内不和你说话
I'm not talking to you for ten seconds.
还剩三秒
You have three seconds left.
听着 你想不说可以不说
You know what?You can give me the silence you want
但别不让我说话...
all you want but you can't give me the talking...
你...你想说什么?
W...What were you gonna say?
刚才你爽了吧...
I hope you had a lot of fun because this...
咱们一刀两断!
This is over!
她把脏舌头...
She violated your orifice...
伸你嘴里了?
with her nasty alien probe?
她做到了 她进你身体里去了
She did it. She went in there All her little embryo alien babies...
那你肚子里就会有小外星人了
are gestating and hatching inside of you.
他们可能正在长大
They're growing right now probably.
你应该赶紧吐出来 马上吐 马上吐
You need to vomit right now. Yak it, yak it.
- 马上! - 你是谁?
- Right now! - Who are you?
我是莱昂纳多·庞塞·莱昂斯皮茨 知道吗?
I'm Leonardo Ponce De Leon Spitz, okay?
我可是关键人物
I'm the key to this.
外星人 他们找来是因为我的网站
Aliens, they want me because of my site.
哇哦!
Whoa!
快跑!
Run!
梅卡拉!
Mikaela!
小心 我们快走
Watch out. We get move.
是炸弹!
It's a bomb!
拿上箱子
We gotta get that box.
进来
This way.
嘿 让我出去 让我出去!
Hey, let me out, let me out!
天啊 你还会这么点火?
Oh my God, you know to hot-wire a car?
- 真性感 - 快开 快开 快开
- That's so hot. - Drive, drive, drive.
她来了 她来了!
She went there, she went there!
等...等!
W...wait!
他们会...
They can....
停 停 停
Cut, cut, cut.
哦 上帝!
Oh God!
亲这个吧 贱货
Kiss this, bitch.
开走 开走 开走 开走
Drive, drive, drive, drive, drive, drive.
好 发生什么事了 好吧
Okay, so what else's going right now, alright,
这些外星人怎么回事?
did you guys just mess with the minor details?
刚才你看到的 还算客气的
Thing you saw back there. That was a little babe.
哇啊! 我的天哪! 我的天哪!
Whoa! Oh my God! Oh my God!
山姆!
Sam!
- 山姆! - 抓住了!
- Sam! - Hold on!
抓住
Hold on.
山姆!
Sam!
我不想死! 我们完蛋了! 哦 我的天!
I don't want to die! We're going to die! Oh my God!
哦 老天! 哦 天!
Oh, Jesus! Oh, jeez!
过来 小子
Come here, boy.
近点
Closer.
好的
Okay.
你记得我 对吧?
You remember me, don't you?
我照你说的做 好吗?
I did what you said, okay?
- 别伤害我们 - 闭嘴!
- Just don't hurt us. - Shut up!
山姆!
Sam!
挖你的肉感觉真不错
It feels good to grab your first.
我会让你慢慢痛苦地死
I am going to kill you, slowly, painfully.
但首先我们有些细致的工作要做
But first, we have some delicate work to do.
我真想把你的胳膊掰断
I could snap your ribs off.
医生 来检查一下这个外星物种
Doctor, examine this alien specimen.
我会扫描你 让我看看你的脸
I'll scan you. Let's take a look at your face.
我是医生 我要情报 交出碎片
I'm the doctor. The odd job Information. Beseeching my shard.
来软的还是硬的?
Easy or tough way?
去那边
Go that way.
讨厌的虫子...
A wormy that's crabby...
哦 就是这个
Oh, there they are.
这是我脑子里的
That's what I'm seeing in my head.
这些符号能指引我们找到能量源
These symbols can lead us to the Energon source.
我们必须得到大脑!
We must have the brain!
放到这桌上 快!
On the table, faster!
大脑? 你们要我大脑干什么?
Brain? What does he mean by my brain?
呃 你脑子里有点东西
Well, you have something on your mind.
是我需要的
Something I need.
等等 我知道你生气
Hold on. I know you're pissed.
我知道你生气
I know you're pissed.
你生气是因为我想杀你
Because I tried to kill you...
这绝对是个误会
and it's completely understandable.
有人想杀我的话 我也会郁闷的
Somebody tried to kill me, I'd be upset too.
我认为完全有机会
I think that we have an opportunity here
重新开始... 改善我们的关系
to start a new and...and develop our relationship,
然后 咱们携手共建和谐社会 好吗?
and...and, see where it leads us, okay?
你就把医生叫回来
So you just call doctor inspection,
5秒钟后我会让你说
I'll let you talk in five seconds.
等...等...
W...Wait...
走 走
Go, go.
走 走 走
Go, go, go.
山姆!
Sam!
走 走 走 走!
Go, go, go, go!
他来了!
Here he comes!
藏起来 山姆! 藏起来
Hide, Sam! Hide.
懦夫
Weak.
小人
Puny.
废铁一堆
Waste of metal.
废物 败类
Junkyard drone.
霸天虎!
Decepticons!
过来 小子
Come here, boy.
还有一个能量源...
There is another source of Energon...
藏在这个星球上
hidden on this planet.
这孩子可以带我们找到它
The boy can lead us to it.
擎天柱!
Optimus!
难道我们种族的未来...
Is the future of our race...
还不如一个人类的生命重要吗?
not worth a single human life?
擎天柱 起来!
Op, get up!
你杀人成瘾了
You'll never stop at one.
我绝不会放过你们
I'll take you all alive.
薄铁皮一张!
Piece of tin!
山姆 你在哪儿?
Sam, where are you?
你太差劲了
You are so weak.
终于 超级领袖都死了
At last, Prime is dead.
山姆 快跑
Sam, run.
汽车人 进攻!
Autobots, attack!
大黄蜂 快带他们离开这儿
Bumblebee, get them out of here.
这是伦诺克斯
This is Lennox.
干得不错
That went well.
主人 那孩子跟丢了
Lost the boy, Master.
汽车人把信号都隐蔽了
The Autobots must be shielding the signals.
- 你说我能靠你做点啥 - 对不起 不
- I can't even rely on you. - Sorry. No.
一个小小的昆虫而已!
What a simple insect!
七十亿人找一个...
What insect amongst severed billion...
闭嘴!
Shut up.
大海捞针啊
It could be anywhere.
那就强迫所有的人类来帮我们找
Then we will force them to find him for us.
该让全世界知道我们的存在了
It's time for the world to know of our presence.
不再遮遮掩掩 不再手下留情!
No more disguises, no mercy!
该轮到我的主人出场了
Time has come for my master's arrival.
霸天虎 出发
Decepticons, mobilise.
时候到了
It is time.
哦 单身就这点好!
Oh, that single's good!
说法语真让人兴奋
Speaking French is so exciting.
哦 我的天 这是谁?
Oh God, who is this?
你好...我是说 呃 下午好!
Hello...I mean, uh, bon...bonswa!
什么? 你谁呀?
What? Who is this?
哦 想气死我呀
Oh, for Pete's sakes.
我可不欣赏...
I'm not impressed with...
你在电话里瞎喘气
your perverted mouth breathing.
(纽约市)
哦 天哪
Oh, jeez.
你在侵犯我的私人空间
You are invading my space.
小心我揍你
I'm gonna have to drop you.
走开行吗?
Would you get out of here?
差点把我吓死
Might freak me out.
我想吃点新菜
We're gonna try new things.
看上去像加拿大天鹅粪
Looks like Candian goosepoop.
你真恶心
It's nasty.
(美国第二舰队 北大西洋)
不错 1-2-5
That's fine, 1-2-5.
那是什么?
What's that.
我来复仇了
Revenge is mine.
(华盛顿特区 五角大楼)
- 听着 航母不可能就这么沉了 - ...恐怖袭击 有更糟的可能
- Look, carriers don't just sink. - ...port accident for a terrorist attack, or worse.
不是 空防方面确认了...
Negative. NORAD confirmed...
投射物来自大气层外
project came from beyond our atmosphere
时速高达三万节
inbound at 30, 000 knot.
地球上的人类
Citizens of the human hive,
你们的领导者掩盖了事实
your leaders have withheld the truth.
在宇宙中你们并不是唯一的
You are not alone in this universe.
我们就在你们身边 隐藏着...
We have lived among you, hidden...
但今后不会了
but no more.
如你们所见
As you've seen,
我们能随意摧毁你们的城市
we can destroy your cities at will.
除非你们交出这个男孩
Unless you turn over this boy.
你们胆敢反抗
If you resist us,
我们必将摧毁整个世界 毫不留情
we will destroy the world, as you know it.
德国政府表示 这段讲话是
What we're hearing from the German government is
通过非法入侵卫星得以播出的
that the world broadcast is a satellite hacking.
军方透露 安全防御级别已升至三级
The military has just told us they have assumed Condition Delta,
是9·11事件以来的最高级别
which is the highest level we've been at since 9/11.
奥巴马总统已飞抵
President Obama is being flown to a bunker,
美国中部的某指挥中心
somewhere in the middle of the United States.
以应对此次全球同一时间
In the phase of the worst simultaneous attacks ever
遭受的袭击
around the globe.
美国罗斯福号航空母舰
The aircraft carrier, USS Roosevelt,
在美国东海岸沉没
goes down off the East Coast
没有生还者
all hands lost.
世界范围内的伤亡人数...
Worldwide casualties are...
大约在七千人左右
in the neighbourhood of 7, 000,
此数字仍在上升
but that number could implode.
尚无法确定
It's still too early to tell.
我们的敌人是谁 为什么攻击
What we need to ask now, is who and why.
联邦调查局仍在寻找这个男孩
The FBI is still trying to locate the boy,
山姆·维特维奇
Sam Witwicky.
他应该知道整个袭击的事情
Within deep, they have information about this.
联邦调查局 中情局 国际刑警组织
The FBI, CIA and Interpol
都在寻求各国...
are all seeking the cooperation...
司法部门的相关协助
of worldwide law enforcements.
嘿 哥们 听听这个 快来看 哥们
Hey bro, you need to listen to this, man.
你得看看这个
You gotta check this out.
他们用交通摄像头
Once they have a traffic camera
...拍到一张山姆·维特维奇的照片
...spotting a Sam Witwicky.
我被拍到了 哥们
They have a picture of me, man.
我们死定了 兄弟
We're dead, bro.
FBI CIA现在正在通缉我们
FBI, CIA, we're wanted fugitives now.
你先看一眼 哥们
I just need you to focus just one minute, man.
现在整个事件的...
This thing is blowing to...
性质升级了 对吧
a whole another level, alright.
- 你知道... - 拿开这东西
- You know one thing... - Remove this thing.
他们能跟踪我们 知道吗?
They can track us. Do you see this?
什么?
What?
他们能跟踪我们?
They can track us?
用卫星跟踪我们?
Like satellite-track us?
喔喔喔 好吧 我都不是你们一伙的
Whoa, whoa, whoa, okay, I'm not even with you guys.
实际上 我是人质
Technically, I'm like a hostage.
这是绑架 我才不会...
This is kidnapping. Enough...
唷 里奥!
Yo, Leo!
你想让我得心脏病 肯定的
This thing's gonna give me a heart attack, I swear.
那是因为你胆子太小
That's 'cause you was a wuss.
是你们逼我上车的吧?
You did force me into the car, right?
- 所以... - 哦 我想你是害怕了
- So... - Oh, I think you scared.
嘿 挡泥板
Hey, Mudflap.
咱们该拿他怎么办?
What are we going to do with this shrimp taco?
一枪干掉 扔后备箱里
Just pop a cap in his ass, throw him in the trunk
没人知道 明白我意思吗?
and nobody gonna know nothing, y'know I mean?
- 等等 我的车... - 嘿 碰碰车
- Wait, now my trunk... - Yo, bumper cars,
听我说 我可全听见了 知道吗?
Check it out. I'm hearing you, okay?
我就在这儿 我能听到你们的话
I'm right here and I can hear you.
你们不会开枪 也不会毁尸灭迹 好吧?
No one's popping any caps in any asses, okay?
今天我真倒霉
I've had a hell of a day.
看看你 连头发都弄不好
Why don't you get a haircut with your bitch ass?
找你的男朋友去吧
Go whine to your boyfriend.
听着 山姆 我知道该做什么
Listen Sam, I know what I'm gonna do, man.
听着 我会去找政府
Look, I'm just going to go to the authorities
告诉他们真相
and tell them the truth.
我跟这一切无关
Like I had nothing to do with this,
- 我是个同伙 - 嘿 嘿!
- I'm an accomplice. - Hey, hey!
是你自愿的 不是吗? 这就是你想要的真相?
You wanted this, right? You wanted the real deal?
因为这就是真相 醒醒吧!
'Cause that's what this is.Wake up!
你脱不了干系
You're in the middle of it.
想走就走 没人拦着你
You wanna run, go ahead, no one's stopping you.
别再抱怨了
Stop complaining.
这是什么意思?
What is the meaning of this?
你敢拿枪对着我?
You dare point your gun at me?
你想跟我打吗? 我要把你撕成碎片!
You want a piece of me? I will tear you apart!
放下武器! 放下武器!
Drop your weapons! Drop your weapons!
叫他们放下枪
Tell them to lower the weapons.
叫汽车人先放
Tell them first.
让他们放下武器!
Tell them to lower the weapons!
少校 我也无能为力
Major, there's nothing I can do.
你自己和他说吧
Talk to him.
你的队伍解散了 少校
Your NEST team is deactivated, Major.
停止对霸天虎的一切对抗行为
You are decease anti-Decepticon operations,
返回迭戈·加西亚基地 还有别的指示吗?
and return to Diego Garcia. Any further orders?
不 我们直接听从...
No. We take our orders direct...
墨邵尔将军的命令
from Chairman Morshower.
好吧 我会见你的上级...
Well, I'll see your chairman...
和参谋总长
and the Joint Chiefs of Staff
但现在你别无选择
but I will raise you...
我有总统的手令
a President of the United States.
你现在必须听我的命令
I have operational command now.
外星人跑到我们星球复仇
An alien blood feud has been brought to our shores
却要我们的战士遭殃
for which our soldiers are paying the price.
真相大白了 我们也参战了
The secret is out. This is our war now.
我们会再次赢得胜利
And we will win it as we always have,
靠的是全面的军事策略
with a coordinated military strategy.
这个蠢货完全想歪了
This fool is terribly misinformed.
这些战士你全都需要
You're gonna get every assets that you've got.
我需要的是作战计划
What we need is to draw our battle plans.
尽一切可能的外交解决途径
What we explore every possible, diplomatic solution.
比如交出那个孩子吗?
Like what: Handing over the kid?
这也不是没有可能
All options are being considered.
毕竟霸天虎都跟来了
Whatever the Decepticons are after,
这只是个开始
this is just the start.
等等 绝不能和他们谈判
Wait, there is no negotiating with them.
你被解职了
I'm ordering you to stand down.
不再需要这个了
You won't be needing this any more.
把你的部队带回基地
Get your assets back to base.
把那堆废铁也带走
Take that scrap metal back to Diego Garcia.
我们走
Let's go.
我真的不喜欢那家伙
I really don't like that dude.
他是个混球
He's a asshole.
汽车人 请到机库报到
Autobots, report to hangar for transport.
铁皮 我们该离开这个星球
Ironhide, we should leave this planet.
但擎天柱并不希望这样
That's not what Optimus would want.
你已经尽力了
There's nothing that you could have done.
- 你还好吗? - 还好
- You okay? - Yeah.
大黄蜂 如果你恨我 我能理解
Bee, if you hate me, I understand.
我弄砸了
I messed up.
对不起
I'm sorry.
年轻人 你是...
Young fella, you are...
...我这辈子最在意的人
...person I care about most in my life.
只要你需要我...
If there's anything you need...
我不会离你很远的
I won't be far away.
他是因为我才死的
He's dead because of me.
他保护了我 可他却死了
He came in to protect me instead.
有些事情你无法改变
There's some things you just can't change.
这样他的牺牲...
So this sacrifice was...
才不会失去意义 哈利路亚!
will not have been in vain, hallelujah!
这一回我决不退缩
We make it right when we turn myself in.
但我们 我们要团结在一起
But we, we've got to stick together.
你不会来真的吧?
You're not gonna do that.
是的 我会的
Yes, I am.
不然我们的努力全白费了
Everything we worked for will be wiped out.
在一天内
In one day.
- 你们俩 - 嗯?
- You two. - Huh?
嘿 认得那些字形吗?
Hey, you know the glyphs?
这些是...
The symbols that have...
我脑子里的符号
been rattling around in my head.
那是古老符号 唷
That's old school, yo.
应该是... 古塞伯坦语
That's like...That's Cybertonian.
哦 这肯定有什么重要的含义
Oh, that's some serious stuff in there.
他们肯定有什么意思 比如信息...
They gotta mean something, like a message...
或者... 像是地图!
or, like a...like a map!
能找到能量源的地图
Like a map to an Energon source.
能读懂吗?
Can you read this?
- 读? 不会 - 你看到吗?
- Read? Nah. - You see that?
不 我们... 我们不怎么会读
No, we...we don't really do much reading.
- 不太会 - 那你们如果不懂
- Not so much. - Well if you can't read it,
那就找懂的人去
we gotta find somebody who can.
哦 看 胆小鬼又回来了
Oh, look, who came stashing and back.
看他发型多搞笑呀 那儿 看
Hair grown like a chip, there, look it.
伙计 我刚才是被吓坏了 行了吧?
I had a bit of a mild panic attack earlier, alright?
那是因为你跟女人似的
That's 'cause you're a pussy.
我是跟着你们...
I think I'm allowed that considering...
一路走过来的
what I've been through...
而且... 听说有问题
and... I heard you have a problem.
我想我能找人帮忙
I think I know someone who can help.
- 谁? - 机器战士网站
- Who? - Robo-Warrior.
机器战士这家伙
This guy, Robo-Warrior...
一切跟外星人有关的
Everything about anything alien,
他都知道
he's supposed to know.
有一次我黑他网站时
One time we hacked this site
好像看见过 呃...
and maybe, I saw some of your, uh...
这种外星人的符号之类的
alien drawings or whatever.
就这儿了
This is it.
嗯 便利店 很好的掩护所
Yep, deli. Good front.
好 稍等
Alright, wait here.
我说进来再进来 好吗?
I'll give you the go, no go, alright?
42号桌点的香肠 犹太馅饼套餐好了
Number 42, we got your kishkakanishka schavanishka and crap-like combo right here.
只收现金 下一位?
Cash only. Who's next?
我告诉过你鲑鱼...
I told you put the salmon...
先用盐水泡再烟熏
in the salt and then smoke.
妈 你想折磨死我啊?
Ma, you want me to cut my handle off or what?
你要了块非常差劲的鱼
You You order a terrible piece of fishing.
我的刀功很棒 就跟忍者一样
I'm like a ninja, with a blade.
给我闪开!
Get out of here!
嘿 山姆! 规矩点 嗯?
Hey, Sam! Watch your reach, huh?
先排号 小伙子
Take a number, young man.
机器战士
Robo-Warrior.
认识他吗?
Know him?
没听说过
I never heard of him.
听说过真实的世界.com吧?
You never heard of TheRealEffingDeal.com?
是那个超级白痴的博客网站
You must be talking about that amateur blog
它的防火墙形同虚设
operation with GameBoy level security.
机器战士
Robo-Warrior.
就是他 就是他! 就是这家伙
It's him. It's him! That's the guy right there.
就是他
That's him.
不是吧
No.
开玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
各位 本店打烊了 全部出去!
Alright, meat store's closed. Everybody out!
出去 现在!
Go, right now!
说你呢 女士 快出去
That means you, lady, right now.
等下 你认识这个人吗?
Wait a minute, you know this guy?
- 我们是老相识了 - 哇啊 老相识
- We're old friends. - Whoa, friend,
就因为你 第七区撤消了编制
you are the case that shut down Sector 7.
全员遣散回老家
Got the tie-bash disbandment,
没有风光的工作
no more security clearance,
没有退休金 一无所有
no retirement, no nothing.
全都因为你
All 'cause of you,
还有和你相好的少女罪犯
and your little criminal girlfriend.
看看她 辣妹一个
Look at her now, so mature.
白痴 鳟鱼在哪儿?
Moron, where's the wifresh?
别让我碰到那些肉
Don't catch me with the thing.
- 亚科夫! - 干嘛?
- Yakov! - What?
再傻站着年终奖金取消
You don't get Christmas bonus just standing around.
你还想攒钱镶新牙吗?
You want those new teeth you saw in SkyMall?
- 当然了 - 那去帮帮她
- It's my dream. - Help around.
你和妈妈一起住吗?
You live with your momma?
不 是妈妈和我住
No, my momma lives with me,
这是两回事
it's a big difference.
电视上全是你的照片 外星仔
They got your face all over the news, alien boy.
- 好 我知道 - 那威震天还活着啊?
- Yeah, I know. - And NBE-1, still kicking, huh?
这是怎么回事?
How did that happen?
别回答 我不知道你的秘密
Don't answer.I don't know what you're hiding,
也不想有任何瓜葛
but I don't want anything to do with it
那么 再见 只当你没见过我
so, goodbye, you never saw me.
我还要做事 赶紧消失
I got bagels to schmidt.
给我五秒钟时间
Well, give me 5 seconds.
听着 等等 我需要你帮忙
Look, hold on, I need your help.
真的 你要我帮忙?
Really, you need my help?
我要...
I need...
好吧 我差点掉了脑袋 明白吗?
Look, I am slowly losing my mind, okay?
那机器人医生把设备
I had a little Crabbot, placed the device
植入我大脑软组织
deep into the soft tissues of my brain,
像家庭影院一样
and started projecting little alien symbols
放映出外星语符号
like a whole freaking movie
而且我还是个逃犯
and on top of that, I'm a wanted fugitive.
你能理解吗?
So you think you got it rough?
你脑子里的图像被投射出来?
You said it projected images of your brain?
对
Right.
冷冻室 快!
Meat locker, now!
- 速冻肉 - 真恶心
- Dead pigs. - Yuck.
你们将看到的是最高机密
What you're about to see is top secret.
千万别告诉我妈
Do not tell my mother.
是死猪 会得病的
Dead pigs, swine flu.
- 不好 - 现在你知道了
- Not good. - Now you know.
下次吃肉的时候
Next time, you eat a goat or a pig.
想想背后的故事
There's a story behind this.
糟糕的真相
Sad little story.
...你说你相信有外星人?
...you're saying you believe in aliens?
好的 资料 资料
Okay, files, files.
我们谈的是符号
We're talking about symbols.
嘿! 还有放射性 别碰
Hey! Still radioactive. Hands off.
好了 小脑瓜
Okay,  Cube-brain.
你看到的是这些符号吗?
Any of these look like the symbols you saw?
你哪儿弄的?
Where did you get these?
我被解雇之前
Before I got fired.
从第七区弄到的独家资料...
I coached S-7's scrawny, drooly...
历时七十五年的外星人研究
75 years of alien research...
指出了一个不容回避的事实
which points to one inescapable fact:
变形金刚
The Transformers...
很久以前就来过地球
they've been here a long, long time.
要证据吗?
How do I know?
考古学家在世界各地的名胜古迹中
Archaeologists found these unexplained markings
发现了这些标记
and ancient runes all over the world.
中国 埃及 希腊
China, Egypt, Greece.
1932年拍的
Shot at 1932.
这些符号见过吗?
These the symbols you're seeing in your head?
- 对 - 一模一样 是吧?
- Yeah. - Same ones over here, right?
那么 告诉我
So, tell me,
谁会留下一样的图案呢?
how did they end up all drawing the same thing?
外星人
Aliens.
而且我觉得有些人就没离开过
And I think some of them stayed.
看看这个
Check this out.
黑刃计划
Project Black Knife.
伪装的机器人一直潜伏在地球
Robots, in disguise. Hiding here.
一直以来
All along.
我们在全国范围内...
We detected radioactive signatures...
均检测到放射性物质
all across the country.
我甚至下跪求第七区对此调查
I pleaded on my knees with S-7 to investigate it
但他们说读数少得可以忽略
but they said the readings were infantesimal.
还说我是在做梦!
That I was obsessed!
我 你能相信吗?
Me, can you imagine that?
威震天说这儿...
Megatron said that there...
还有个能量源
was another Energon source here.
- 地球上? - 地球上
- On Earth? - On Earth.
另一个能量源?
On another source?
好的 还有个能量源
Okay, and that these symbols,
而且我这里的符号地图能够指路
the maps in my head would lead him there.
你和汽车人说了吗?
Should you talk to your Autobot friends?
没有 没有 他们是后来的
No, no, no, the source is before.
不管能量源是什么
Whatever the Energon source is,
他们比汽车人早
it predates them. It's before them.
- 所以比他们更早 - 正确
- So it comes before that. - Correct.
那么 好吧...
Well then, report...
除非问一问霸天虎
Unless we can talk to a Decepticon.
我是说 你倒是不用跟它客气...
I mean, I'm not on speed terms or whatever...
其实 我有个
Actually, I am.
让我出去!
Let me out!
- 让它吃点苦头 - 打开
- It could be a little bit sad. - Open it.
我找一帮霸天虎踹死你!
I'm gonna so many Decepticons on your butt!
老实点
Behave.
- 这也是霸天虎? - 对
- What is it, a Decepticon? - Yeah.
- 你能训练他吗? - 我试试
- Can you train him? - Tried to.
我花了毕生的精力
I spent my whole adult life,
寻找外星人
coming a plan of aliens.
而你却带个外星人
And you're carrying it around
却像遛狗一样
what are you supposed to make a little chihuahua.
想打架吗 你这个卷毛?
Wanna throw it down, you pubic fro-head?
对不起 抱歉弄坏你的眼睛
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry about your eye.
你知道 如果你能老实点
You know, but if you're a good boy,
我就不弄瞎另一只了
then I'm not gonna torch your other eye.
好吗? 我不折磨你
Okay? I'm not gonna torch it.
告诉我这些符号是什么
Just tell me what these symbols are.
求你了
Please.
好吧
Okay.
哦 我知道 这是超级领袖的语言
Oh, I know that. That's the language of the Primes.
我读不了 但是呃 这些家伙...
I don't read it, but uh, these guys...
你在哪儿找到的照片?
Where the frick did you find photos of these guys?
- 就是他们吗? - 对
- Is this them? - Yeah.
首批探险者 伙计 资格最老的
Sakers, pal. Oldest of the old.
哦 他们几千年前
Oh, they've been here for thousands of years,
就到这里找东西
looking for something.
不知是什么 也没有人告诉我
I don't know what, nobody tells me nothing.
哦 他们可以翻译这些符号
Oh, they'll translate those symbols for ya.
我知道他们在哪儿
And I know where to find them.
快说吧
Show us.
最近的在华盛顿
Closest one's in Washington.
美国航空航天博物馆
Smithsonian Air and Space Museum.
我的梦想国度
Land of dreams in there.
我曾梦想当名宇航员
All I ever want to be was an astronaut.
- 拿着 - 那是什么?
- Hold those. - What is that?
什么?
What?
我穿上它壮胆
I wear them when I'm in the funk.
杰姆比也是 骗子 这是运动员的装备
So does Jeamby, Cheater. It's a baseball thing.
好了 对好表
Okay. Once you synchronize,
高度警惕 少上厕所
shop-mind and empty bladder
万一被抓 上了法庭...
you get caught, demand an attorney...
可别供出我来
and don't ever say my name.
给 吃一片
Here, take one of these pills.
放在舌头下面
Slip it under your tongue,
这是饼干里用的...
it's a high-concentrate polymer...
高浓度巧克力
they put in Oreo cookies.
用它骗测谎仪屡试不爽
Fools the polygraph, everytime.
好了 我们上路吧
Okay, now let's get this show on the road.
不 听着 我不能干这个
Whoa, no, listen. I can't do this.
我不想抓外星人 好吗?
I'm not some alien bounty hunter, alright?
因为我不想干这个 守卫有枪
'cause I'm not gonna do this. Guards have guns,
我不想死
I don't want to die.
孩子 孩子 孩子 孩子
Kid, kid, kid, kid, kid, kid.
你要是打退堂鼓 你就死定了
You compromise this mission, you are dead to me.
看着我的眼睛
Now look into my eyes,
收紧括约肌
and tighten up that spare tank.
博物馆要关门了
The museum is now closing.
嘿 我麻烦了 兄弟
Yo, baba, bad news, bro.
纸用完了 你这儿有吗?
Ran out of toilet paper, you got any out here?
拜托 一定要有...
Please tell me you...
先生 我建议你回去那里
Sir, I suggest you get in there.
马上要闭馆了
The museum is closed.
听着 我也理解你们
Listen man, I understand that,
但你也看到了 这事很重要
but as you can see, this is important.
我要解大手 我会走的 好吗?
Dumper-dumper. I gotta go, alright?
先生 你可是一个成年裸男 现在还在到处走...
Sir, you are a grown naked man around showing...
穿上你的裤子并离开...
Pull your pants up and exit...
我哪儿也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
你有纸吧 对不 先生?
You got that paper, right, sir?
你就不害臊吗
You should be embarassed.
这是个对家庭开放的博物馆 先生
This a family museum, sir.
这儿怎么回事?
What is going on here?
你能忍受几次这样的疯子?
How many times can you get tased in the nuts?
那你去把着门 嗯 你知道
So you covered the gates, huh, you know.
你是个业余的 有水平的外行
You're an amateur man, a rank amateur.
现在有五个警卫 五个警卫
There's now five guards. Five guards.
你拿着这个并离开这里
You get this stuff and get out of here.
给我一秒钟
Give me a second.
有人在跟踪我 好吧
I gotta get the tracker, alright.
- 老实点 - 我有幽闭恐怖症
- Be good. - I'm claustrophobic.
看 看 跟着他 跟着他
Look, look. Follow him, follow him.
他知道他要去哪儿
He knows where he's going.
- 他知道什么 - 什么?
- He knows something. - What?
他知道什么!
He knows something!
- 你知道我指的吗? - 对
- You got what I got? - Yeah.
黑鸟
Blackbird.
他来了
There he is.
这家伙可是个奇迹 就像...
This guy's a legend, like...
就像董事会主席一样
like the Chairman of the Board.
对 菜鸟 把碎片放上去
Yo, freshman, put the shard.
看看会发生什么
And watch the magic happen.
哦 坏了 这是霸天虎!
Oh shit, it's a Decepticon!
- 霸天虎? - 这是什么?
- Decepticon? - What is it?
快躲那边去!
Find the main tail!
这什么陵园啊?
What sort of hideous mosalleem is this?
回答我 你们这帮虾兵蟹将 滚出来!
Answer me pawns and knaves, show yourselves!
不然就修理你们!
Or suffer my infinite wrath!
等-等 你们这些微型脊椎生物
W...wait, old spinal called based organisms.
闪开!
Bugger!
记住我天火的永恒光辉!
Behold the eternal glory of Jetfire!
启动远程系统自控
Prepare for a systems' override.
告诉你 这家伙老糊涂了
I tell you, this guy did not age well.
我想他不会伤害我们
I don't think he's gonna hurt us.
我命令打开这些门
Command these doors to open.
开火!
Fire!
哦 我说了 开火!
Oh, I said, fire!
蠢货
Bollocks.
打开它 这些没用的东西...
Break that, these worthless...
等一下
Wait a second.
我屁股又痒得要命
Itchy, wretching, rust in my arse.
哦 这一回博物馆会非常生气
Oh, the museum's gonna be very angry.
非常生气 我们得上飞机!
Very angry. We gotta catch that plane!
我在执行任务
I'm on a mission.
- 等...等 等等! - 等一下 等等 等等
- W...wait, wait! - Wait, wait, wait.
- 嘿! - 你们要干什么?
- Hey! - What do you want?
听着 我们只想谈谈!
Look, we just want to talk!
我没时间谈 我在执行任务!
I've no time to talk, I'm on a mission!
我这样的人见人怕
I'm a mercenary goon-bringer.
- 这是哪个星球? - 地球
- What planet am I on? - Earth.
地球? 真是太难听了
Earth? Terrible name for a planet,
还不如叫“土球”
might as wellcall it "dirt".
土的星球
Planet dirt.
告诉我 机器人还在打内战吗?
Tell me, is that robot civil war still going on?
- 谁赢了? - 霸天虎
- Who's winning? - The Decepticons.
那我转投汽车人那边了
Well, I changed sides to the Autobots.
“转投”是什么意思?
What do you mean, "changed sides"?
这是个选择
It's a choice.
这是经过激烈思想斗争的选择
It's intensely personal decision.
霸天虎太消极
So much negativity.
光靠仇恨怎么活啊?
Who wants to live a life filled with hate?
你是说不想再跟着
Meaning you don't have to work for those
那些霸天虎混了?
miserable, freaking Decepticons?
霸天虎要是胜利了
If they set on their way,
将毁灭整个宇宙
they destroy the whole Universe.
我也转投汽车人了 我也转投了
I'm changing sides, I'm changing sides,
我的女神战士!
Warrior Goddess!
谁是你的小汽车人?
Who's your little Autobot?
哦 你真可爱
Oh, you cutes.
叫我小威
Name's Wheelie.
来叫我名字 叫我名字!
Say my name, say my name!
它这么乱来
What are you allowing to...
你都能忍?
happen to your foot just now?
它至少专一 山姆
At least he's faithful, Sam.
好 它不仅专一
Yeah, well, he's faithful,
还没脸没皮
and he's nude and he's perverted.
你消停会儿行吗?
Can you just...Can you stop?
嘿 你在干什么?
Hey, what are you doing?
我不想多啰嗦
I don't wanna argue it.
你在说什么?
What were you saying?
我告诉你我叫天火!
I told you my name was Jetfire!
所以别惹我
So stop judging me.
有人一大早心情就不好
Someone shit in the bed this morning.
- 看看这家伙 - 我情绪是有问题
- Look this guy. - I have issues of my own.
都是我妈遗传的
Pretty stout with my mother.
我的祖先来这已经几个世纪了
My ancestors have been here for centuries.
我父亲他是第一代转轮! 第一代转轮!
My father, one was a wheel! The first wheel!
- 知道他变形成什么吗? - 不知道
- Do you know what he transformed into? - No.
什么都变不了! 但是他死得光荣 死得其所...
Nothing! But he did so with honor, dignity, damn it...
我的助推器坏了
My boosters are fried.
我觉得我们应该互相帮助
I thought we could help each other.
你懂的我不懂
You know things I don't know.
我懂的你不懂
I know things you don't know.
- 真的 - 我觉得他什么都不懂
- I do. - I don't think he knows anything.
说实话 我不知道
Honestly, I don't know.
我每天都和这些为伴 它们在我耳边萦绕 在我眼前浮现
I could do this all day It comes in waves these vivid symbols,
虽说是符号但我都记在我脑子里
They're symbols but they are in my mind.
看 都在我脑子里
You see, all this is in my mind.
威震天逼我记下来
And Megatron wants what's in my mind.
他和一个叫堕落金刚的干的
Him and someone called the Fallen.
堕落金刚? 我知道他 是他留我在这儿生锈的
The Fallen? I know him. He left me here to rust.
那个霸天虎
The original Decepticon.
它可不好惹
He's terrible to work for.
满脑子都是毁灭 混乱 危机...
He's always apocalypse, chaos...
他的怀疑 也是我任务的一部分
His suspects, they were a part of my mission
堕落金刚要找 想起来了
the Fall and Search, I remember now.
要找匕首之尖和一把钥匙
Of a dagger's tip and the key!
慢点 匕首之尖 钥匙
Slow down. The dagger's tip, the key,
你在说什么?
what are you talking about?
没时间说啦
No time to explain.
抓紧了 大家
Hold on, everybody!
哦 也不太糟糕
Well, that wasn't so bad.
我看错了个星球
I was overseeing the wrong planet.
嘿 太疼了!
Hey, that frickin' hurt!
噢 我的天!
Oh, my God!
噢 天哪!
Oh, God!
哦 我的天! 你那美丽的脸庞...
Oh, my God! You beautiful face,
这真是完美的一刻
this will be a perfect moment.
只是你降落在了我的睾丸上
Except you landed on my testicles.
拜托你下来!
Please get off!
我的蛋蛋!
My balls!
山姆!
Sam!
- 我们在哪儿? 西蒙! - 嘿! 好!
- Where are we? Simmons! - Hey! Yeah!
哦 我的天
Oh, my God.
这是什么? 是拉斯维加斯!
What is this? It's Vegas!
- 都还好吗? - 都好!
- You guys okay? - Yeah!
嘿! 到拉斯维加斯了!
Hey! I think we're in Vegas!
真的 真的很疼
That really, really hurts.
你很走运 我没伤着
You're just lucky that I didn't get hurt.
这样是要死人的 知道吗?
People could've gotten killed, okay?
我要是伤着了
And if I would have gotten hurt,
- 我老妈会问候你... - 哦 闭嘴!
- you would have heard from... - Oh, shut up!
我说了要架个时空桥梁
I told you I was opening the space bridge.
这样到埃及才会快
It's the fastest way to travel to Egypt.
你在说什么? 你什么都没跟我们讲!
What did you tell us? You didn't tell us anything!
你什么都不说 还来埃及干吗?
You didn't tell us anything. Why are we in Egypt?
你还敢对我那么没礼貌 小混蛋
Don't you dare slip in with me, fleshwing.
我原来告诉你了
You would do the informed.
能听我说两句吗?
Can you just stop for a second?
听得清吧? 你说说为什么来埃及
Can you focus? Can you tell us why we're in Egypt
至少得让我们...
so we can all have a little bit...
都有点心理准备吧?
assemblance and peace of mind?
这个星球我们机器人以前就来过
This planet was visited by our race once before
第一代祖先百万年前就来过
by our earliest ancestors a millenium ago.
他们的使命是...
They were on an exploratory mission...
收集能量块
to harvest Energon,
那是机器人的生命之源
the life blood of our race.
没有它我们会腐烂 氧化 生锈 就像我这身架子
Without it, we'll all perish, oxidize and rust,
你们知道慢慢腐朽而死
Do you have any idea what is...
有多痛苦啊?
like a slowly fall of parton die?
你别总跑题行吗? 老先生
Let's not get episodic, okay? Old-timer.
从头到尾简单说出事实和细节
Beginning, middle, end.
把来龙去脉说清楚
Facts, details, condense, plot, tell it.
在沙漠的某一处地方
Somewhere buried in this desert,
我们的祖先建了个巨型机器
our ancestors built a great machine.
通过摧毁恒星来获得能量块
It harvests Energon by destroying suns.
- 摧毁恒星? - 把太阳炸掉?
- Destroy suns? - You mean blow them up?
对 你看 开始的时候
Yes. You see, in the beginning,
曾经有七位超级领袖
there were seven Primes,
都是第一批领袖
our original leaders.
他们进入宇宙...
And they set out in the Universe...
寻找其它星系的恒星
seeking distant suns to harvest.
这些超级领袖有一个原则:
The Primes set out with one rule:
决不摧毁有生命的星球
Never destroy a planet with life.
但后来有一位违背了这项原则
Until one of them tried to defy this rule.
他的名字就是“堕落金刚”
And his name, for ever more, was the Fallen.
他不顾人类死活
He despised the human race.
想启动那个机器...
And he wanted to kill you all...
来消灭人类
by turning on that machine.
而激活它的唯一途径就是传说中的钥匙
The only way to activate it is with a legendary key
也就是我们所说的领导模块
called the Matrix of Leadership.
领导模块的归属问题
A great battle took place...
引发了一场鏖战
over possession of the Matrix.
堕落金刚比其他超级领袖更强大
The Fallen who was stronger at his will did,
其他超级领袖只能...
surrendered no choice,
偷出领导模块藏起来
but to steal and hide it from him.
他们做了最后的牺牲
In the ultimate sacrifice,
以生命为代价将领导模块封藏
they gave their lives to seal the Matrix away
藏于用他们遗体铸成的坟墓里
in a tomb made of their very own bodies.
这座墓没有人知道在哪儿
A tomb we cannot find.
就在这沙漠某处
Somewhere, buried in this desert,
埋藏着那台特别的机器
that deadly machine remains.
堕落金刚知道位置
The Fallen knows where it is.
如果他找到了超级领袖的墓
And if he finds the Tomb of the Primes,
你们的世界将不复存在
your world will be no more.
那怎么阻止他?
Okay so how do we stop it?
只有超级领袖能打败堕落金刚
Only a Prime can defeat the Fallen.
比如擎天柱?
Optimus Prime?
你遇到过超级领袖吗?
So you met a Prime?
你遇到的肯定是超级领袖的后代
You must have met a great descendant.
他还活着吗?
Is he alive?
在这个星球上吗?
Here? On this planet?
他为了救我牺牲了自己
He sacrificed himself to save me.
那么他死了
So he's dead.
没有超级领袖就完了
Without a Prime, it's impossible.
没人能阻止堕落金刚
No one else could stop the Fallen.
这个能量若能...
So the same energy that's going to be...
重启那台机器...
used to reactivate the machine...
那它能用来...
Could that energy somehow be...
激活擎天柱
used to reactivate Optimus...
让他重获新生吗?
and bring him back to life?
设计之初并没这么考虑
It was never designed for that purpose,
但这种力量非比寻常
but it's an energy, like no other.
在霸天虎抓到我之前
So then how do you get us to the Matrix
你怎么带我们找到领导模块?
before the Decepticons get to me?
用你的脑子 地图 符号
Follow your mind, your map, your symbols,
你在地上写的 都是线索
what you got in the sand, it's your bloom.
曙光照耀在匕首之尖的时候
When dawn alights the Dagger's tip,
三位国王将打开入口
three kings will reveal the doorway.
找到那入口!
Find the doorway!
快去!
Go now, go!
这曾是我的使命 现在是你的使命了
That was my mission. It's your mission now.
要在霸天虎找到你我之前
Go before the Decepticons find me
先找到入口
and find you.
中情局我有个线人
That was my CIA contact.
说古代苏美尔人称亚喀巴海湾
Says Ancient Sumerian used to call the Gulf of Aqaba
- 为匕首之尖 - 那是匕首之尖
- the Dagger's Tip. - That's the dagger's tip.
- 它是红海的一部分 - 明白
- It's part of the Red Sea. - Got it.
一刀为二分出埃及和约旦
It divides Egypt and Jordan like the tip of a blade.
北纬29.5度 东经35度
29 and a half degrees north.35 east.
就是这儿
There it is.
好的 首先得把...
Okay, first thing we gotta do...
擎天柱给弄过来
is get Optimus to Dagger's Tip.
怎么带着他...
How are you gonna get him...
绕过大半个地球?
halfway around the world?
我打个电话
We're gonna make a call.
有警察
We got the cops.
我不想进监狱 哥们!
I can't go to prison, guys!
山姆 你得离开这条路 避一避
Sam, you gotta get off this road and lay low.
兄弟 他们会发现的
Man, they'll pick up.
这不就是忍者的伪装术嘛
This is just called blending in like a ninja.
我赏你一巴掌怎么样?
How about I'll lay my piss in your face?
他们走了
They're gone.
没时间了
Wait another time.
打电话给伦诺克斯
How are you gonna make the call to Lennox?
你可是全球通缉犯
You are in the worldwide.
他们要是埋伏在其中一个基地
What, they're gonna tranquil in one base?
他们马上就会发现你的
They'll track you here in seconds.
中情局就蜂拥而至
CIA is all over this place.
那你来打?
You're gonna call?
好主意 这... 主意不错
Okay, that's...that's a good idea.
- 好吗? - 我是说 我只是...
- Alright? - I mean I just was...
想的有点多了
My mind in other things.
比如你怎么没在监狱里被杀
Like why don't you get being chipped in prison.
(新泽西州)
启程时间: 21点
This departure:2100 hours.
所以我们要开回基地
So we're shipped in back to base.
中心危在旦夕
This is central at stake.
伦诺克斯少校 电话
Major Lennox, phone call.
伦诺克斯 孩子在我旁边 那孩子 明白吗?
Lennox, I'm with the kid. The kid, you know?
很有个性的那个
One with the attitude break.
我们要那卡车 卡车
I need the truck. The truck.
我们有可能让他起死回生
We got a possible resurrection going on over here.
你想不到我们在哪儿
You're not gonna believe where we are.
线索是法老 图坦卡门
Code Tot, as in King Tutankhamen,
一美元的背面
back of a $1 bill.
空降坐标如下 北纬29.5度 东经34.88度
Coordinates for air-drop, 29.5 north, 34.88 east.
明白 写下来 定下来
Get it.Write it down, write it.
哦 我的天
Oh, my God.
我得走了 好吧 我恨警察
I gotta go, okay. I hate the cops.
等-等 你是谁?
W...Wait, who are you?
等下 是我 里奥 我 里奥 里奥
Wait, it's me. Leo, me, Leo, Leo. Leo.
警察来了 我们快走
The cops are coming right now. We need to go.
坐标 北纬29.5度 东经34.88度
Coordinates 29.5 north, 34.88 east.
红海的要地 亚喀巴海湾
Tip of the Red Sea, Gulf of Aqaba.
是埃及
Egypt.
你确定吗?
Are you serious?
长官
Sir.
即使我们真的...
Even if we could figure...
把这大家伙运到那儿
out a way to get big man over there.
光靠那小孩...
How is this little kid's...
就能把他救活吗?
supposed to bring him back to life?
我不知道
I don't know.
但必须相信他
But we gotta trust him.
好 我们再复述一遍
Okay, let's go over it again.
当曙光照耀在匕首之尖的时候
When the dawn arise the dagger's tip,
三位国王...
the three kings...
...将打开入口
...will reveal the doorway.
这是他原话 知道意思吗?
That's what he said. You know what that means?
- 不 不知道啊 - 我也不清楚
- No, what does it mean? - I have no idea.
哦 我的天 哦 糟了 检查站 检查站
Oh my God, oh my God. Checkpoint, checkpoint.
我没带护照
I don't have my passport.
护照 笨蛋!
Passport. Idiota!
上面有摄像头
They have cams at top.
这就是他们要找的人
He's the one that they want.
好了 放松 得友善一些
Alright, chill. Let's be nice to them.
我能搞定 这都是我的人
I can handle it. These are my people.
- 好 - 我有1/36的阿拉伯血统
- Yeah. - I'm one thirty sixth Arab.
哦 很好 一个矮冬瓜
Oh great, a frickin' munchkin.
哦 小个子都这样 告诉他 他很高
Oh, little people are mean. Tell him he's tall.
- 你要什么? - 我想去...
- What do you want? - I want to go to...
匕首之尖 对吧?
The Dagger's Tip, right?
埃及 约旦 我们想去那儿
Egypt, Jordan. We wanna go there.
我和我的家人 这是我的家人
Me and my family. This is my family.
- 这是我大儿子 二儿子 - 嗨 你好
- This is my son, my other son. - Hi there.
我的女儿
My daughter.
我们是来旅游的 从纽约来
We're tourists from New York.
- 纽约? - 对 对
- New York? - Yes. Yes.
五十公里就到
50 kilometres.
我们去买一个你们的炸豆丸子 谢谢!
We're going to get one of your falafels, thank you!
好的 谢谢你
Yeah, thank you very much.
- 纽约 - 我知道 我们在哪儿见过你
- New York. - I know, I know you from somewhere.
阿诺 把这线索传给中情局
Arnold, Put it on the wire to the CIA.
霸天虎 男孩的位置...
Decepticons, boy's location.
已经探明
Detected.
红蜘蛛跟着
注意隐蔽
Undercover, yo,
你得把自己伪装起来
you gotta blend in with your surrounding.
和周围融为一体
You know, you gotta be part of the landscape.
壮观
Awesome.
应该是外星人建的
I think aliens built that.
对 对 对
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
来 快点! 快点
Go, move it! Move it.
- 什么? - 嘿 保护我们
- What? - Hey, guard us.
低调点 别一惊一乍的 好吗?
Low-profile, don't make a scene, okay?
某些人有活儿要干啦!
Yeah, some of us got work to do!
笨蛋汽车人
Dumb Autobots.
(NEST部队 预计到达时间 早上6点)
做我女朋友其实挺危险
Being my girlfriend is hazardous to your health.
没错 女孩就喜欢爱冒险的男生
Yeah, well, girls like dangerous boys.
- 真的? - 对
- Really? - Yeah.
你还是把那个字说出来吧
You might as well just say it.
女士优先
Ladies first.
好吧 你今晚很绅士
Okay, so tonight, you're gonna be a gentleman.
挺有风度的
You're really chivalrous.
为什么生我的气?
Why are you mad at me?
你知道吗? 宝贝 我没...
You know what? Baby, I'm not...
我没生气
I'm not mad.
我飞了三千公里...
You realise that I just flew 3, 000 miles...
就是不想看到你死
to keep you from getting killed.
我知道
I know.
谁还能当你女朋友?
Who else could be your girlfriend too?
看看我们所经历的一切
Look at the things that go through with me.
现在我们有月光和星光
And now we're underneath the moon and the stars
有地球上三个最漂亮的金字塔
and the three most beautiful pyramids on the planet
你还是不肯说你爱我
and you still can't even tell me that you love me.
- 怎么? - 等等
- What? - Wait.
你又转移话题?
Why do boys always change the subject?
金字塔和星星...
The moon and the stars...
- 山姆... - 跟我来 快
- Sam... - Come with me really quick.
西蒙 里奥 快醒醒!
Simmons, Leo, wake up!
听着 天文学课本第47页
Listen, Astronomy class, page 47,
你还记得吗?
you remember the class?
不 不 我只上了两天大学
No, no, I was only in college for two days,
你记得什么?
you remember that?
对 呃 起来 起来 过来
Yeah, well, get up. Up, up.
他说什么呢?
What are you talking about?
看到那三颗星星了吗?
Can you see those three stars?
最下面一颗贴着地平线?
You see how the last one touches the horizon?
那是猎户座
That's Orion's belt.
也叫做三王星
It's also called the Three Kings...
那是因为...
and the reason for that is...
三位埃及国王...
the three Egyptian kings who...
专门在吉萨建造了金字塔
built the pyramids in Giza built them
来对应三颗星星
to mear those stars.
它们像箭一样摆在咱们面前
So it's like an aerial staring straight in the face.
他们指向东方 约旦的方向
They all point due east towards Jordan.
指向佩特拉的群山
The mountains of Petra.
引擎发生故障
We got a seatbelt malfunction.
已向中央司令部紧急报告...
We gotta have to divert...
减轻负载 准备跳伞
Flight in lower, prepare for bail-out.
跳伞 跳伞 跳伞 跳伞?
Bail-out, bail-out, bail-out, bail-out?
好了 所有人 背好降落伞
Alright, team, grab your shoots.
跳伞?
Bail-out?
用过军用降落伞吗?
Familiar with the standard MC-4?
当然没有 我没在这么好的...
Of course not. I've never jumped...
飞机上跳过伞
out of a publicly good airplane before.
等一下 你不是捉弄我吧?
Wait a minute, is this really happening?
嗯
Yeah.
等等 等一下
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
是你在背后搞鬼 是吧?
You're behind this, aren't you?
说什么呢?
What are you talking about?
按广播说的办 这些人可不会胡闹
You heard the pilot. These guys don't mess around.
这是工作流程
This is standard procedure.
我只是奉命行事
I'm just following orders to the letter.
这不是你说的吗?
Do you know what you said?
看来你真是不想干了 少校
You, just find the captain and your career, Major.
等等 那是什么? 那是什么?
Wait, what was that? What's that?
情况不妙
That's not good.
快点 这边来 这边!
Come on. Right this way, right this way!
我不能跳下去
I can't jump out of an airplane.
- 我有溃疡 不行啊  - 来吧 没事儿
- I have an ulcer! No, no. - Come on. It's okay.
我真的不行 你这是干什么...
I really can't do this. What are you doing...
这边来 来啊
Come here. Come here.
你怎么不带降落伞?
Why aren't you wearing your chute?
我必须要保证最重要的人先走
Because I have to secure the VIPs first.
好了 我希望你能全部听清楚
Okay, I want you to listen very carefully.
记住我跟你说的每句话
Remember as everything that I say.
每个降落伞都有GPS
East to the GPS trackers,
所以救援人员能找到你
so you can be found by search and rescue.
降落伞边上有条带子
Right next to that's a fabric webbing called
叫控制绳 拉开它...
a bridle which holds the pin...
就能打开主背囊
that keeps the main container closed.
- 听明白了吗? - 我听不清
- Look, are you listening? - I can't.
- 别吵 - 好吧 好的
- Stop that! - All right. All right.
当飞机遇到气流膨胀了
When the plane that shoot inflates into the air,
它会拉动锁扣打开降落伞
pull the pin and open some air,
红色的备用 蓝色是主伞
break your rack up, lose your primary.
我要你拉蓝色的
I want you to pull the blue.
你可要使劲拉
I need you to pull it really hard.
不 别现在拉 你还在飞机上 白痴!
Not right now. We're on the plane, you dumbass!
他说再见了吗?
Did he say goodbye?
没有 没来得及说
No, he didn't even say goodbye.
将军 我们已就绪
General, we're loaded and ready.
你一旦下令
You give us the go,
五分钟后开始行动
and we'll be ready to press in five minutes.
- 很好 - 长官
- Excellent. - Sir,
你看这个 看
you need to see this. Now.
这个坐标在哪儿?
Have we checked these coordinates?
在埃及 长官 他们在那里空降
Egypt, sir.They're air-dropping in.
开什么玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
他知道些什么
He knows something.
如果他要行动
We need to be ready to back him up,
我们会给他支援
if this thing goes hot.
收到
Copy that.
中情局找到那个男孩了
CIA just got a hit on the boy.
距伦诺克斯空降点
Hundred miles from the location on...
仅一百英里 那地方可够热闹的
that little map there. It's getting hotter.
它应该... 就在这附近了
It's gotta be...around here somewhere.
这也太壮观了
You see the size of this?
- 看到了吗? - 不可思议
- You see this? - Spectacular.
太棒了 看看那边
Amazing. Look at that.
就是这儿 各位
It's here somewhere, guys.
哦 是吗 为什么?
Oh yeah, why?
那个机器人自己都老糊涂了
'Cause we're trusting Grandpa Blackbird
都不知道他自己在什么星球上
who doesn't even know what planet he's on.
说实话 这是我这辈子
On his defense, this is the biggest doorway
见过的最大的门了
I've ever seen in my entire life.
好吧 呃 不错
Okay. Well, that's great.
我先彻查下 好吧?
Let me do a quick search, alright?
不
Nope.
坏消息是 伙计们
Ever questioned mind, guys,
考古学家已经来过了
that archaeologists have been here before.
这儿什么都没有
There's nothing here.
生活免不了痛苦和绝望 孩子
You realise it's heart-break, despair, kid.
有时候 你付出了很多
Sometimes, you get to the end of the rainbow
但老天爷就是要开玩笑
and the leprechauns went and booby-trapped it.
你还说我 你都还离不开你老妈
I'm listening to you, you live with your mother.
- 还没有结束 - 结束了 完了
- It's not over. - It is over. It's done.
为什么你们总是说傻话?
Why are we still listening to your little punk-ass?
我是说 有这功夫还不如把我的轮子弄漂亮点?
I mean, what kind of dumbfucks accept ding my rim?
干掉威震天 如何?
Kill Megatron. How about that?
呃 他没完成心愿 你知道 我的意思
Well,he doesn't get the job done, you know, I mean,
- 因为他被打了 兄弟 - 你害怕了?
- 'cause he's zapped, man. - You scared?
什么 害怕? 我害怕你那张丑脸
Well, scared? Scared of your ugly face.
我丑? 呃 咱俩是双胞胎 蠢货
I'm ugly? Well, we twins, you stupid genius.
来啊 来打我
Bring it, then! Get off me!
我要给你整形
I'll change your face around!
我要把你屁股翻过来
I'll get all up in that ass!
兄弟们! 哦 嘿!
Guys! Oh, hey!
你喜欢这滋味吗?
You like the way that feels?
- 那不疼 - 你明白吧 嗯?
- That ain't hurt. - You got that, don't you?
我要起来了...
I'm getting up...
- 不要 大黄蜂 - 大黄蜂 听着
- Come on, Bumblebee! - Bumblebee, listen.
真是太无礼了
Now that's rude.
哦 天哪! 是符号
Oh, my God! The symbols.
大黄蜂! 射穿它
Bee! Shoot it.
- 看看 - 看看这些
- Check this out. - Look at it.
- 哇! - 这就是天火说的元老
- Wow! - This is the part which they found silicon.
超级领袖的坟墓
The Tomb of the Primes.
领导模块
The Matrix.
不
No.
千年宝物化为灰烬
Thousands of years turned to dust.
结果不该是这样
This isn't how it's supposed to end.
听到了吗?
Hear that?
美国空军 C-17s
US Air Force. C-17s.
什么是C-17?
What's a C-17?
擎天柱救不活了 什么都没了
You can't bring it back, Sam, there's nothing left.
看 你看看周围
Look, look around you.
我们所做的一切
We didn't just go through everything...
都事出有因
we went through for no reason at all.
结局并不重要
They just haven't end like this.
重要的是我们来这里的原因
There is a reason that we're here.
我大脑里的声音和符号指引了...
The voices and the symbols in my head led us here...
目标
for a purpose.
大家跟着我 是因为我有线索
Everyone's after me because of what I know.
而我所知的 就是这个管用
And what I know, is that this is going to work.
你怎么知道会管用?
How do you know it's going to work?
因为我相信它
Because I believe it.
你们最好让我离开这架飞机
Best put me out of this plane.
在放大家伙了 山姆!
He's dropping the big one. Sam!
你用这些黑沙子
You think you can bring him back...
就能救擎天柱?
to life with that pixie dust?
当然可以 走吧!
Absolutely. Let's go!
走!
Go!
快点!
Move it!
大家友好点!
Remember your friendly!
把擎天柱隐蔽起来!
Cover Optimus!
全村警戒 把弹药放到这来
Secure the village. Get those cases down here.
布置狙击手和导弹
Get snipers and Stingers up high.
我们把这十吨重的机器人
So he just dropped off ten tonnes of dead robot
运到这不毛之地
in the middle of nowhere.
希望这孩子心里有数
Hope this little kid know what he's doing.
对 我也这么想
Yeah, me too.
发现目标! 大黄蜂 四公里
Got a visual! Yellow tee, four klicks.
发信号弹!
Hot-flare!
他们在哪儿 看到吗?
That's them right there. You see the flare?
就在那儿! 看到吗?
Right over there! See it?
男孩已找到
不
No.
山姆!
Sam!
哦 上帝 求求你 上帝
Oh God, please God,
- 拜托! - 里奥 别说了!
- please! - Leo, stop freaking out.
不要再叫了!
Just stop freaking out!
把这家伙扔下去吧 嗯?
Just drop this guy off, huh?
求你了 让我活着 别让我死
Please let me live, just let me live.
闭嘴!
Stop freaking out!
马上停止尖叫 就是这样
Just stop screaming right now. That's it.
受不了这家伙了
Can't take that guy anymore.
躲到灰尘里 灰尘
Hide in the dust. The dust.
我们得分开
We gotta split up.
大黄蜂 你上去
Bumblebee, you are the decoy.
引开霸天虎 好吗?
You lead the Decepticons away, alright?
我去找擎天柱
I'm gonna get Optimus.
我和双胞胎车去把他们引开
I'll help throw their fire away.
你找那些士兵去
You get to those soldiers.
希望你能成功 孩子
I hope that dust works, kid.
谢谢
Thank you.
他转回来了
It's turning around.
他回来了 他回来了
It's coming back, it's coming back.
交给我了
It's up to me.
一个老光棍 爱国却被抛弃
One man, alone, betrayed by the country he loves,
可在危难时刻又成为最后的希望
now its last hope in the final hour of need.
准备由一代宗师驾驶你吧
The pants are to be driven like never before.
大师风范
Under my skin.
嘿 嘿 嘿! 哪儿也别去
Hey, hey, hey! Don't go nowhere.
- 开车! - 你干不了这个 孩子
- Drive! - You will never make it, kid.
光靠勇敢是不够的
Bravery will only get you so far.
你电晕过我 对吗? 你欠我的
You tased me, okay? You owe me.
- 我要去 - 好吧 好吧
- I'm go. - Okay, okay.
我是考验你的 你过关了 好吗?
That was a test. You passed, alright?
那东西带着霸天虎的标志
Thing's got alien tattoos all over.
不是空军
That ain't Air Force.
那是什么鬼东西?
What the hell was that?
- 漩涡1号 回复 - 有人在吗?
- Eddy-1, copy. - Anyone there?
谁在上面?
Who's up?
- 回复 - 通信中断
- Copy. - Radio's down.
不起作用了
It's dead. Counter that.
电磁脉冲干扰
EMP-burst.
看看今天在这鬼地方...
Let's see how this day is going...
会发生什么
in this godforsaken desert.
你好 长官
Yes, sir.
伦诺克斯少校叫我把电话转给你
Major Lennox told me to pull the cord.
我知道 长官
I know, sir.
我... 我现在在哪个国家?
W...Which, what country am I in right now?
美国
United States.
不 不 不是美国
No, no, not the United States.
我就是从美国来的
I'm from the United States,
鬼知道是什么地方 四周都是驴
I'm in the middle of nowhere, surrounded by goats.
呃 那是我们的好朋友 盖洛威
Well, that was our good friend, Galloway.
看来他有点不高兴
He's less than pleased.
真是怪了 我们联系不到伦诺克斯
How is it that we can't reach our men,
他怎么能在那...
but he can reach me...
寸草不生的埃及沙漠里联系到我们?
from some random Egyptian desert?
没有
Nothing.
迈克 发求救信号
Mike, put an SOS,
告诉卫星我们需要帮助
let the eye in the sky know we need some help.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
准备气罐 多放点烟 好让那个孩子找到我们
Pop some more flares so that the kid can find us.
看 就是那儿 我们快到了
Look. There he is. We got a couple of miles.
伦诺克斯的队伍拥有最先进的量子通讯器材
Lennox's team has the latest in quantum crypto gear.
谁能告诉我
Can somebody tell me...
为什么我们连简单的通信连接都不能够建立?
why we can't establish simple radio contact?
我们正在尝试所有...
We're hailing them on every frequency...
可用的频段和模式 长官
and mode in the book, sir.
那个区域的卫星已经不能工作了
Our satellites in the area have gone blind.
我们正在努力 长官
We're working it, sir.
见鬼
Dammit.
想想别的方法
Something's not right, it doesn't add up.
联系约旦人
Contact the Jordanians,
看看能否派空军前去
see what their assets they've got in the area.
还有联络埃及的萨勒姆将军
And get Egypt's General Salaam,
让他派出无人侦察机
ask him to clear some USV
飞越埃及领空
over-flights in Egyptian airspace.
我们现在需要各方协助确认地点
We need an assist in confirming visuals now.
无人机起飞
Scramble predators now.
B-1号 起飞
B-1, rotate.
还有一英里
East on the mile that way.
来这里
Come here.
这边
This way.
- 一个...老光棍... - 别再说了
- One man... alone... - Stop saying that.
爱国却被祖国抛弃
betrayed by the country he loves.
哦 我的天啊
Oh my goodness,
我还在车里呢 好吧? 你不是一个人
I'm in the car, okay? You're not alone.
放松 我可是大师
Just relax, you're looking nice well.
我... 我觉得他们已经被甩掉了
I...I don't think he's still following us.
那是你觉得
That's what you think.
主人 很遗憾地告诉你个坏消息
Master, sorry to be the bearer of bad news,
他们把擎天柱运来了
but the soldiers brought the body of Prime.
那男孩肯定找到领导模块了
The boy must have the Matrix.
不能让他接近擎天柱
We cannot let him reach Optimus.
霸天虎们!
Decepticons!
我们开始攻击!
Begin our assault!
有情况!
We got incoming!
保持好队形 加强火力!
We got a whole load of flight coming our way!
- 有多少? - 大概十三个
- How many? - We got 13 to count.
不吉利 真不吉利
This ain't good. This ain't good.
我们这回可惨了
We 'bout to get our asses whooped.
那些霸天虎正在寻找山姆
Alright, those Decepticons are searching for Sam.
不管他拿到了什么
Whatever he has,
他肯定能够救活擎天柱
he thinks it'll bring Optimus back to life.
我们任务就是找到他
So our mission is to find him...
带他到擎天柱这
and get him to Optimus.
好 我们由左翼吸引火力 我需要侦察队
Alright, we're gonna draw fire from the left flag.
我带队
I need a scout team.
我 阿尔茜和铁皮
We'll walk through the middle...
从中路上去
with Arcee and Ironhide.
当你们看到空中支援时
Alright, when you see the precious cargo,
释放绿色烟雾后
I want you to pop green smoke...
你们就穿过那些柱子回来
and come back to those pillars.
我们打个伏击战
We'll have the ambush set.
好的 出发 出动!
Alright, let's go, move out!
看过五七年那部...
Did you see that film...
这是《OK镇大决斗》的经典枪战片吗?
"Gunfight at the O.K. Corral"?
- 柯克·道格拉斯主演 - 没有 怎么了?
- Casting Kirk Douglas. - No, why?
我们和他们处境一样
Looks like we're right in the middle of it.
结果好吗?
Is that good?
很多人都死了
Lot of people died.
哦...
Oh...
- 哦... - 躲起来!
- Oh, oh, oh... - Hide!
我的天!
Oh my God!
- 准备好 - 老天
- Hit the deck! - Oh, my God!
山姆 山姆
Sam, Sam.
他们没看到我们
I don't think they saw us.
蹲下 蹲下
Get down, get down.
好 听着 我们现在以最快速度
Okay, once, it's clear, we'll run for Optimus
跑到擎天柱那儿 好吗?
as fast we can, okay?
要是不行怎么办?
And what if it doesn't work?
一定能行
This will work.
是啊 但是如果不行呢?
Yeah, but what if it doesn't?
一定行的 一定行!
It's gonna work. It'll work.
上 上 上
Up, up, up!
准备跳
Radio shell.
还有半英里
We got a half a mile.
士兵们不知道我们在这儿
I don't think the soldiers know we're here.
撤退!
Fall back!
铁皮 到中间来
Ironhide, up for middle.
铁皮 快走
Ironhide, move it.
走! 走 走!
Go! Go, go!
大力神
Devastator!
我们无路可走了 我们要死了!
There's no way to go. We're gonna die!
听着 就算要死
Listen, we're going out.
我们也要死得像个爷们 明白吗?
We're going out like men, understand?
我们要死了!
We're gonna die!
- 哦 - 你瞧这家伙...
- Oh. - Look at this motherf...
霸天虎真差劲!
Mean robots suck!
坚持
Hang on!
回来!
Get back!
抓住! 别放开
Grab it! Don't let go.
坚持 老哥 我抓住了
Hang in, man, I got this.
我不想死 我不想死
I don't want to die. I don't want to die.
我使鹰爪功 鹰爪功 你奈何不了我
Kung fu grip, boy. Kung fu grip. You ain't getting me.
他被吃了 他真没用
He did. He got so waste.
现在知道谁厉害了 嗯?
Ho, who's your daddy now, huh?
他被整个都吃了...
He got all ate up...
唯一安全的地方就是它的下面
Well, the safe place is right under it.
朝它跑 朝它的脚跑!
Run it. Run for his feet!
你就不该吃我 我要把你的脸砸烂
You're never eating me. I'm gonna bust your face up.
没人敢惹我 小心你的脸!
Nobody's tested me. In your face!
接着打 哥们
Take five, Mudflap.
哦 天哪!
Oh my God!
咿哈!
Yeehaw!
没人能欺负双胞胎兄弟
Nobody messes with the twins.
我抓到你了
I got you.
伙计 你打到我的脸了!
Ow, man, you shot me in the face!
- 呆在下面! - 对 呆在它下面
- Stay under it! - Yeah, stay under it.
狂暴 把陷阱设置好
朱迪!
Judy!
- 山姆! - 什么?
- Sam! - What?
山姆!
Sam!
山姆! 山姆!
Sam! Sam!
山姆!
Sam!
- 山姆 - 爸爸!
- Sam. - Dad!
等等! 等等!
Wait! Wait!
请听...
Please listen...
我要你跑! 快跑!
I want you to run! Run!
- 爸爸 别说了! - 快离开这里
- Dad, just stop! - Get out of here.
- 他们要的不是你们 是我 - 快跑!
- They don't want you, they want me. - Just run!
哦 天哪 等等!
Oh God, wait!
- 山姆·维特维奇 - 等等
- Sam Witwicky. - Wait.
这是你想要的 你要的是这个
This is what you want. You don't want 'em.
- 快走! 快走! - 求你们别说了! 别说了!
- Go! Go! - Please, stop! Stop!
- 为什么你... - 快离开这儿!
- Why don't you... - Just get out of here!
别伤害他们
Just don't move.
我知道你
I know you.
快走! 快走!
Just go! Just go!
我知道你要的是我
And I know what, you need me.
因为我知道领导模块
Because I know about the Matrix.
- 别这么做 山姆 听我说 - 拜托 爸
- Don't do it. Sam, listen to me. - Please, Dad.
他们一样会杀了我们
They're gonna kill us all anyway.
嘿 嘿 看
Hey, hey. Look.
你想要的东西 在我这里
This is what you want. I'm here.
大黄蜂!
Bumblebee!
救命!
Help!
杀了他 大黄蜂 杀了他
Kill him, Bee. Kill him.
呆在一起 妈妈 到这儿来
Stay tight, Ma. Come on. Get in here.
- 大黄蜂? - 在
- Bee? - Yeah.
嘿! 我不知道发生了什么 但我们必须得离开
Hey! I don't know what's going on,but we gotta move.
- 快跑! - 这里肯定有出路的 快来
- Run! - There's gotta be a way out of here. Come on.
- 退后 退后 退回去 - 朱迪
-  Get back, get back, get back. - Judy...
靠着墙 靠着墙 靠墙
Against the wall. Against the wall. Against the wall.
大黄蜂! 大黄蜂!
Bee! Bumblebee!
你把他们带到安全的地方 好吗?
You get them somewhere safe, alright?
你们到车里去 那里安全
You gotta get in the car. You can be safe.
不 现在还争什么争
No, listen to my discussion.
- 你是我的儿子 对吧? - 我知道!
- You're my son, alright? - I know!
你是我的儿子! 我们要在一起
You're my son! We'll all go together.
- 听着 - 我们要在一起
- Listen. - We're all going together.
爸 别说了 好吗? 你们快上车
Dad, stop, okay? Get in the car.
他会把你带到安全的地方 要是不安全 就跑
He's gonna get you to safety. You don't, you run.
别停下 也别躲
You don't stop, you don't hide,
使劲跑 听到我说的了吗?
you run. You hear what I'm saying?
好吗? 你们安全了我就来
Okay? I'll find you when you're safe.
- 不 - 让我去做该做的 爸爸
- No. - You gotta let me go, Dad.
让我自己来
You'll have to let me go.
- 我必须自己来 - 荣恩
- You have to. - Ron.
荣恩 荣恩! 让他去吧
Ron, Ron! Let him go.
你一定要回来!
Just come back!
- 走吧! - 走吧!
- Come on! - Come on!
梅卡拉 梅卡拉!
Mikaela, Mikaela!
- 跟他们一起去 - 我不会跟他们去的
- Go with my parents. - I'm not gonna go with them.
- 援军来了! - 我们有救了!
- We got Jordanians! - We got help!
卧倒
Down!
你没事吧 士兵?
You okay, soldier?
我们来帮你 士兵
We're gonna help you, soldier.
把飞机里的伤员救出来!
Let's get being moon and clear the birds!
别动 别动 先别动
Stay still, stay still. Don't move.
你还好吗 年轻人?
You alright, young man?
- 有无线电吗? - 有...
- You have a radio? - Yes...
嘿 孩子 认识你还是很高兴的
Hey kid, it's been nice knowing you.
记住我为我的国家所做的
Remember what I did for my country.
该我上场了
This is my moment.
你疯了!
You're crazy!
大约两分钟内到达指定位置
ETA to station, two minutes.
- 放在主屏幕上显示 - 长官 是 长官
- Put it on the main screen. - Sir, yes, sir.
捕食者无人机 一号
Predator's air-one.
哦 糟糕 上当了
Oh shit, it's a trick.
给我下令开始“烈焰”行动 传达到每个人
Commence Operation Firestorm. Send everyone.
海军陆战队准备出发
Get those boys out of the ground.
我是总部...
This is 101 in strike packages.
展开攻击编队 轻装上阵
Fast course river. Execute lightly.
- 看到山姆了 - 快点 别拖拉!
- Spotted Sam. - Hurry, don't slow up!
铁皮!
Ironhide!
跟着我们去柱子那边 我们带你去擎天柱那里
Follow us to the pillars. We'll take you to Optimus.
小心!
Look out!
山姆 到柱子那边!
Sam, get to the pillars!
我们走
Let's go.
哦 天啊 在那儿
Oh God, this is it.
金字塔就建在机器上面
The pyramids built right over the machine.
他们启动机器...
They turn that machine on...
太阳就没了
no more Sun.
我可不答应
Not on my watch.
我绝对不答应
我是美军斯滕尼斯号航母舰长 请报明身份
USS Stennis, identify.
嘿 你到底在哪儿?
Hey, where the hell are you?
什么 在看气象频道吗?
What, you're on a weather channel?
还是体育新闻 情景喜剧还是什么?
Sports center, high-dreaming TV or something?
我们有三百颗卫星在天上
We get a pretty hundred satellites up there.
可我们的人都在哪儿?
Where the hell are all our men?
请报上你的身份
Identify yourself.
你叫什么 水手?
What is your name, sailor?
怀尔德 我是美国海军...
Wilder, Captain of the USS...
斯滕尼斯号航母的舰长
John C. Stennis Aircraft Carrier.
好吧 怀尔德舰长
Okay, Captain Wilder,
我是特工西蒙
this is Agent Seymour Simmons,
第七区的头
head of the Sector Seven.
有个极其强大的外星人
There is a mother of all non-biologicals
正准备摧毁太阳
getting ready to blow up our Sun.
你是要继续跟我争论...
You want to have fooled down...
官阶高低
about my lack of clearance,
还是去拯救亿万人的性命呢?
or you want to help save a gazillion lives?
好吧 西蒙 我听着呢
Alright, Agent Simmons. I'm listening.
五公里
Five klicks.
海湾以西
West of the gulf.
一个外星人正在摧毁金字塔
We got ourselves a dalion remodelling a pyramid.
我们唯一的希望就是那门的轨道炮
I want hopes of prototype weapon pull a rail gun...
- 能以七倍音速击穿钢板 - 这属于机密
- shoots a steel projectile at Mach 7. - That's classified.
别跟我说什么机密 好吗?
Don't talk to me about classified, alright?
如果你的船到了海湾 你就明白了
Now if you've got a battleship in the gulf
叫他们准备发射武器!
you tell him to ready that weapon!
呼叫基德号 驱逐舰
Contact Destroyer, USS Kit.
这里! 过来!
This way! Move it!
- 我们应该去哪儿 长官? - 组成攻击队形
- Where do you need us, sir. - Protect those in the line of fire.
快点! 快!
Let's go! Go!
把无线电给我 快点
Give me your Comms. Come on.
埃普斯!
Epps!
就现在 我们需要空中支援 愈快愈好
Right now, we need air support, ASAP.
我们的士兵在20英里以北...
Have troops in contact 20 miles northwest Radar contact...
联系的区域 88区 AS
Grid on contact. Proceed 88, Alpha Sierra.
美军轰炸机 090 你可以准备投放联合攻击弹药...
USS Stenin 0-9-0, you are approved to drop a 2,000...
- 情况怎么样? - 我没能带他们回来
- What you got?  - I couldn't get to them, sir.
他们正向柱子这边跑来 还有600米
They're 600 minutes away and they're heading right for the pillars.
好的
Alright.
空中支援快到了
Precious cargo's coming.
行动!
Move!
山姆
Sam!
发现山姆
Spotted Sam.
快点!
Come on!
两两火力掩护 有两个人 十二点方向
2-2, covering fire. Two civilians, twelve o'clock.
掩护我们
Cover for us.
好 保持空袭火力 我们在营救那两个人
Okay, air strike. We'll rescue the civilians.
快点 过来!
Come on. Get up!
快点!
Come on!
进去
Get in here.
让我们到这儿来
Oh look who showed up.
你最好给个充分的理由
You better have a good reason for us to be here.
擎天柱在哪儿?
Where's Optimus?
他就在院子那边
He's right over there, across the courtyard.
那我就去找他
I got to get to him right now.
不 没有空中掩护
No, we got an air strike coming.
我必须马上见到他
I have to get to him right now.
退后 退后
Come here, b-back.
我来也
Incoming!
安全着陆
Stick the landing.
瞧瞧我天火的英姿吧!
Behold to the only Jetfire!
现在让我给大家展示一下如何让敌人痛苦
Now let me show you how we brought them pain in my day.
我太老了
Too old for this crap.
继续前进
Keep going.
十五回合的战斗
15 minutes of fighting.
我就在大力神的蛋蛋下面
I am directly below the enemy's scrotum.
海平面上25.7米
25.7 metres above sea level,
北纬29.32度
29.32 north.
- 发射轨道 5-2 5点方向 - 目标锁定
- Field track, 5-2, 0500 o'clock. - Target acquired.
保持锁定 2号轨道
Killing track two.
锁定 发射
Lock. Fire.
耶! 耶!
Yeah! Yeah!
B-1轰炸机 30秒后接近目标...
B-1, stand on my target. 30 seconds...
我们现在必须转移了 明白吗?
We're gonna make a break for the beast on my command, okay?
你们两个就跟着我跑 明白吗?
You guys stick with me, you understand?
一步也不许离开
You stay on my ass.
希望那些F-16别打的太准
Hope these F-16s got good aim.
嗯 怎么了?
Yeah, why is that?
我告诉他们橘红色烟雾为打击目标
I told them to hit the orange smoke.
你是说橘红色的烟雾吗?
You mean that orange smoke?
我这次没扔准 不行吗?
It wasn't my best toss, okay?
- 快跑! - 快跑!
- Run! - Run!
来啦!
Incoming!
快点
Come on.
死吧!
Die!
山姆!
Sam!
别开火!
Hold your fire!
山姆!
Sam!
走开! 快去叫救护车
Get out! Get me an EVAC.
快想想办法
Fucking do something!
- 山姆! 山姆... - 山姆!
- Sam! Sam... - Sam!
快点 我们走 我们走 快点!
Come on, we got to move. We got to move! Come on!
我要看看我孩子 那是我儿子
I have to see my kid. I got a son.
山姆!
Sammy!
准备! 电击 准备! 电击
Clear! Take a shot. Clear! Take a shot.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
别再这样
Do it again.
山姆!
Sam!
好了 听我的声音 我爱你 我需要你
Okay, listen to my voice. I love you and I need you.
拜托 拜托 为了我回来 山姆 拜托! 我爱你!
Please, please come back to me. Sam, please! I love you!
我死了吗?
Am I dead?
我们一直在关注你 很长很长时间了
We have been watching you. A long, long time.
你为擎天柱而战斗
You have fought for Optimus,
我们唯一的后代 你英勇无畏 不怕牺牲
our last descendant, with courage and with sacrifice.
具有领袖精神
The virtues of a leader.
我们值得将秘密托付给你
A leader worthy of our secret.
领导模块不是被发现的
The Matrix of Leadership is not found.
而是努力
It is earned.
回到擎天柱身边
Return now to Optimus,
将领导模块融合到他的火种源中
merge the Matrix with his Spark.
那是你此生注定的命运
It is, and always has been, your destiny.
山姆
Sam.
我爱你
I love you.
孩子 你为我而回来
Boy, you returned for me.
活着的领导者!
A living Prime!
简直不敢相信
I don't believe it.
领导模块是我的
My Matrix.
站起来 站起来 站起来
Get up, get up, get up, get up.
站起来 擎天柱!
Get up, Prime!
- 哦 不 - 他要启动机器
- Oh, no. - He's turned on the machine.
你要阻止他 站起来!
You gotta stop him. Get up!
擎天柱!
Optimus!
堕落金刚 我的主人
Fallen, my master.
我的那些兄弟们这次可挡不了我的道了
My brothers could not stop me from this.
- 对 - 现在 太阳是我的了
- Yes. - Now I claim your sun.
向金字塔顶射击
Enemy target, top of pyramid.
行动 行动 行动
Engage, engage, engage.
很快 我们的力量会更强大
In moments, we'll be at siren strength.
我这辈子没干过什么有意义的事
All my Decepticon life I never did a thing worth doing until now.
擎天柱 收下我的礼物
Optimus, take my parts.
这能量之强大 你无法预料
And you'll have a power you've never known.
请完成你的使命
Fulfill your destiny.
汽车人 通电!
Jolt, electrify!
移植加力燃烧器
Transplant those afterburners.
出击
Let's roll.
开火 瞄准金字塔!
Fire. Take it off to the pyramid!
这个星球将永远陷入黑暗中
This planet will be dark forever.
和你的兄弟们一样去死吧
Die like your brother.
他们也是你的兄弟
They were your brothers too.
红蜘蛛...
Starscream...
你选错目标了!
You picked the wrong planet!
拿下你的面罩
Give me your face.
成王败寇
I rise. You fall.
不 不
No. No.
我不想劝你做胆小鬼 主人 但有时侯
Not to call you a coward, Master, but sometimes,
胆小鬼往往能生存下来
cowards do survive.
这不算完
This isn't over.
经历了这一切你才愿意说你爱我
You took all of this for you to tell me that you love me.
你先说的
You said it first.
谢谢你 山姆 你救了我的命
Thank you, Sam, for saving my life.
别客气
You're welcome.
谢谢你信任我
Thank you for believing in me.
我们的种族因为被遗忘的过去而走到一起
Our races united by a history long forgotten.
齐心协力面对未来
And a future we shall face together.
我是擎天柱 在此发出倡议
I am Optimus Prime, and I send this message
让这段历史流传下去
so that our past will always be remembered.
我们拥有珍贵的记忆 生生不息
For in those memories, we live on.
很高兴你能来听课 爱因斯坦教授
So glad you can join us, Professoer Einstein.
对 最近有点忙
Yeah it's kink of busy.
好了
Okay.